♫  Columbia Pictures Fanfare playing  ♫
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
(respirator whooshing
rhythmically)
(rhythmic beeping and whooshing
continue)
(creaking)
(cries softly, sniffles)
(animated music plays on TV)
♫  ♫
The boom slang was stolen
from the zoo last night.
It's extremely dangerous.
(rhythmic beeping and whooshing
continue)
(sighing)
(P.A. beeps)
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
(rhythmic beeping and whooshing
continue)
Father.
Any news on my grandson?
No change.
He hasn't woken up.
A father's job is to protect his family.
When Wataru was on that roof...
(policeman talking over
speaker)
when he was pushed...
(people chattering)
where was his father?
Wataru is lucky.
You never know what horrible fate
your bad luck has saved you from.
(breathing heavily)
{"Stayin' Alive" by Avu-Chan
playing}
Improved by Sailor420
Hope you enjoy the show
{"Stayin' Alive" sung
in Japanese}
♫  ♫
♫  Stayin' alive
stayin' alive  ♫
(song continues in Japanese)
♫  Stayin' alive...  ♫
(phone line ringing)
(song fades)
(phone line clicks)
Maria: Thank you for taking
the job on such short notice.
I am ready.
You are getting
the new and improved me.
Since I've been working
with Barry,
I am experiencing a calm
like never before.
Never.
Like, I'm less reactive
to situations,
I'm more accepting
of people's shortcomings.
I was a little uncertain
about coming back to work,
but it's like Barry says;
You put peace out in the world,
you get peace back.
Maria: I think your new
therapist might be forgetting
what you do for a living,
little ladybug.
Ladybug?
Mm-hmm.
Your new operational name.
Ladybug? Really?
You don't like it?
You like it?
I like it.
Well, if you like it, all right.
Oh, I see what you're doing.
Ladybugs are supposed
to be lucky. Ha, ha.
(horn blaring)
(squishing)
(groans)
Maria: You don't have bad luck.
Really?
My bad luck is biblical.
I'm not even trying to kill
people and someone dies.
Maria: That's an exaggeration.
Ladybug: It is? My last job?
The political blackmail photos?
(woman moans)
(woman) I voted for you.
Remember the suicidal bellboy
climbed to the roof
of his hotel,
couldn't take it anymore?
(bellboy screaming)
(Ladybug grunts)
Maria: Seems more like
his bad luck than yours.
(bellboy groaning)
Hang in there, buddy!
Maria: And he didn't die.
Okay? You drove him
to the hospital.
It's good luck.
All in how you frame it.
Sure.
Gotta say I like it here.
I could live here.
I like the atmosphere,
the people are considerate.
(grunts)
(metallic clinking)
Except for that guy.
Why is this job paying so well?
It was supposed to be carver's,
but he's got some stomach thing.
Carver?
You know,
and he doesn't
do snatch and grabs.
I'm filling in for carver?
Y-You picked me second
to carver?
You said you wanted simple
for your first job back.
Doesn't get simpler.
Shit.
Maria: Shit what?
I think I must have
lost the key when that guy
bumped into me.
What's the number again?
Maria: Five twenty-three.
Momonga: (on screen) Momomon.
Carver.
What an ego.
I mean, talk about a candidate
for self-improvement.
I mean, calling in sick?
I mean, what is that,
high school?
Maria: Mm. I can hear
that personal growth.
I know I'm being judgmental.
I need to... work on that.
But, Jesus, what a douche bag.
(watches ticking)
Maria: You have the strangest
requests... firecrackers?
I'm industrious.
Please tell me you didn't
order the sleeping powder.
Nope.
You almost gave that bodyguard
in Anchorage a heart attack.
I've worked on the dosage.
Take the gun.
♫  ♫
(people chattering)
Ticket please.
Kimura: Hai.
(woman over speaker) This train
is bound for Kyoto.
Thank you for using our train.
First class is that way.
Hai. Domo.
Maria: I'm gonna assume
you didn't take the gun?
Barry says every conflict
is an opportunity
for a peaceful... what was it?
And your handler says
some conflicts require a gun.
(chiming over speakers)
Shit.
(announcements in Japanese
over speakers)
(passengers chattering)
Ladybug: Okay, I'm on.
Maria: Well, that's a start.
Hey, this is nice.
Economy?
You know, I'm thinking
of starting my own agency.
You know, all simple jobs,
all the time.
Maria: That's a
terrible business plan.
No more sociopaths,
no more maniacs.
Just quality people.
Barry says it's time for some
change. I think he's right.
Barry does not know
what you do for a living.
Okay, here we go.
The bullet train has 16 cars;
Ten economy, six first-class,
and remember, only one minute
stop at every station.
(low, muffled chatter)
Bloody fuckin' hell.
Do you mind?
(Kimura and woman
speaking Japanese)
What is he,
fucking blind or something?
Lemon: Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
Oh, come on,
nicking...? No.
You don't have to Nick
the biscuits, man.
(woman speaks Japanese)
Oh, no.
You all right?
Okay, cool.
Yeah. Fucking asshole.
Thank you.
Why'd I do that?
It's like I got a compulsion
or something.
I have to take it if I see it.
Need to talk to someone.
Serious.
A goldfish biscuit?
I mean,
I don't, I don't understand it.
Okay, simple snatch and grab.
What am I snatching
and/or grabbing?
Maria: A briefcase.
Intel says there's
a train sticker on the handle.
Briefcases have owners.
Owners are not simple.
Mm-hmm. And last update says
the owners will be
in economy class.
O-Owners, plural?
Why didn't you tell me
to bring that gun?
I did. You chose
spiritual enlightenment.
(speaks Japanese)
Please.
Ticket. (sighs)
Hold on.
(paper rustling)
(in English)
Ah, no, no. Receipt.
Oh. (sighs)
Shit, I think
I dropped my ticket, too.
Uh, that receipt shows
I bought a ticket,
though, right?
One stop.
Yep.
Domo a rig at...
I thought they bowed here.
(door whooshing)
(panting)
I PUSHED HIM. FIRST CLASS, SEAT B4
♫  ♫
(gasps)
Sorry, kid. I'm looking for...
(stun gun clicking)
(Kimura grunting)
(grunts softly)
You found her.
(whooshing)
Oh, lemon.
Tangerine.
You're bleeding, mate.
Oh, mate, shit.
Oh, shit, man.
Oh, fuck.
Who the fuck did I kill?
Get a wet one on it
or something.
Oh, it's not mine, mate.
Oh, it's not yours?
Yeah. I don't bleed.
Oh, in that case,
just leave your jacket open,
let everyone have
a good old look.
Yeah, I want everyone
to see my tie.
Yeah, yeah.
Fuck is wrong with you?
Pull your coat together
so no one else notices, lemon.
I think they'll notice
the childish code names first.
But if we're gonna
stick with fruit,
why not, uh, apple or orange?
So, what's in this case?
Maria: Are we doing this?
You know what's in the case.
(sighs)
Money.
It's always money.
Tangerine: Tangerines are sophisticated.
Oh, now he's callin' a fruit
sophisticated.
Yeah, it's cross-hybridized
with other fruit.
They're adaptable.
(sniffs)
Like me.
Ladybug: You said six cars in economy,
say 30 passengers per car,
guessing two bags per,
let's see, uh,
times two and you carry...
Yeah, no fuckin' way
I'm gonna find one brief...
Wait.
Maria: What?
Train sticker on the handle?
Yeah.
Holy shitbox.
And why am I lemon?
Tangerine: 'Cause you're sour.
No one likes lemons.
That's bollocks, mate.
Lemonades, lemon drops.
You got a sore throat?
Lemon meringue pie.
When was the last time
you ate a lemon meringue pie?
Lemon drizzle cake.
I'm sorry,
are you talking about lemons?
(whispering)
I have the case.
Maria: Well, that's great.
Is it?
Yes.
What's the catch?
There is no catch.
There's always a catch.
Get off the train.
Quite like lemons,
I just hate code names.
(man sighs)
Oh, well, look at this.
Sleeping beauty.
Tangerine: Wakey-wakey.
Lemon: Eggs and bakey.
Where am I?
♫  ♫
You're safe now.
Your father sent us.
You idiots work for my father?
Ooh, easy.
We could deliver you back
to your pops in a box.
Technically,
we're outside contractors.
I'm tangerine.
He's lemon.
Like the fruit?
You ever watch
Thomas the tank engine?
Here we go.
Hey, you watch
something nowadays,
what is it, huh? Nothing.
It's twists, violence, drama,
no message.
What's the point? Huh?
What are we supposed to learn?
Everything I learned
about people
I learned from Thomas.
Oh, yeah? And you bring
your sticker book, did ya?
I always bring my stickers
with me, you know that.
Take tangerine here.
He's a Gordon, this blue one.
And Gordon is the strongest,
the most important,
but he doesn't always
listen to others.
What's that, now?
I mean, some people
are Edwards; Wise, kind.
Some are Henrys; Hardworking,
strong.
Some people are diesels.
Fuck me!
Those are trouble.
You, though...
Yeah, you seem like a Percy.
Young. Sweet.
Not all there.
(chuckles)
(feigns chuckle)
Tangerine: You finished, both of you?
Yeah.
Right.
Your daddy hired us
to get you out of the trouble
you got yourself into,
didn't you, naughty boy?
Why are you... wh-why are you
t-tangerine, though?
Oh, it's sophisticated, mate.
Oh, fuckin' hell.
It's not important, is it?
What is important
are the 17 dead bodies we left
getting you back from
the triad that kidnapped you
with the plans to ransom you
to your extremely psychotic
fucked-up father.
Actually, it's 16.
What's that, now?
Sixteen kills, mate.
No, it was 17.
It's... 16.
Lemon, you're startin' to get
on my tits.
Sixteen.
I'll smash my fucking head
through a brick wall.
That'd help your memory...
It was 16.
The fuck is wrong with you, man?
It was 17, goddamn it.
I want to strangle you now.
You mind if we do this now?
We'll get it sorted.
Oh, don't worry about him.
Couldn't give a shit.
Go ahead.
♫  I'm forever  ♫
♫  blowing bubbles  ♫
(man screaming)
One.
(gunshot)
(grunts)
♫  Pretty bubbles in the air  ♫
Two and three.
(screaming)
♫  They fly so high  ♫
♫  nearly reach the sky  ♫
(muffled shouting)
Five guys playing poker.
♫  Then like my dreams
they fade and die  ♫
♫  fortune's always hiding  ♫
♫  I've looked everywhere...  ♫
lemon: No.
Lemon: Keep moving!
Big guy.
Yeah, big guy.
♫  Blowing bubbles  ♫
(straining) Sometime today!
♫  Pretty bubbles  ♫
Ten.
♫  In the air  ♫
(tires screeching)
Three assholes with swords.
(yelling)
Fucking get it. Fuck!
Lemon: Why do you always bring swords?!
Fucking triad.
I mean, you would, wouldn't ya?
You son of a bitch!
(grunts)
I like swords, actually.
(engines revving)
(tires squealing)
Looks like it's time
for a Jaffa cake.
How about a wagon wheel?
Oh, that works.
♫  Fortune's always hiding  ♫
swing!
♫  I've looked everywhere  ♫
Fourteen, fifteen.
♫  I'm forever blowing bubbles  ♫
And the prick on the motorcycle.
♫  Pretty bubbles in the air  ♫
♫  pretty bubbles  ♫
So 16.
You forgot the poor,
innocent civilian on the street.
The fuck you...?
Hey, buddy. Hey, buddy.
You okay? Oh, my...
♫  pretty...  ♫
(song stops abruptly)
Shit.
That wasn't our fault.
That wasn't our fault. No.
Wasn't our fault?
Well, what would Thomas
the tank engine say, lemon?
That's really mean.
He'd say, "hey,
take responsibility, mate."
He doesn't sound like that.
(imitates train whistle)
Gonna put a little distance
between me and the owners.
Maria: Are you nervous?
Yeah, I'm nervous.
You sound nervous.
'Cause I am, in fact, nervous.
Hey, listen,
I'm just gonna get off
at the next stop.
Lemon: Oh, let's, uh,
have a seat, then, huh?
Do you know what they call
your papushka?
Course I fucking do.
The White Death.
Not exactly a fruit.
No. There you go.
There's a story...
Stop me if you've heard it...
Where this woman found herself
in the unfortunate position
of owing your father
a tidy sum of money.
Now, the issue was
it took her some time
to acquire this money.
But she did pay it back
five minutes late, didn't she?
Yeah, what'd he do?
Cut their arm off.
Fuckin' hell!
Yeah.
He said she owed him a finger
for every minute.
(stifled laughter)
Oh.
Anyway, he's not a monster.
He didn't make her
sit through it five times.
He just cut once, didn't he?
(zip tie whizzes)
Ow.
This is too easy.
Maria: You're over thinking it.
You're under thinking it.
It's not a word.
Yes, it is.
Really?
I think it is.
Did you Google it?
Ladybug: Doesn't matter.
Maria: What would Barry say?
Barry would say,
"a negative outlook
leads to a negative outcome."
Maria: Wow. How much
do you pay him again?
Tangerine: Our job is to keep you safe
and to recover the briefcase
with the ransom money inside.
And I plan on completin' my job
and keeping...
Lemon.
Lemon: Hmm?
Where's the briefcase?
Oh, I stashed it.
The case, lemon.
Go get me the fucking case.
Hmm. You're a liability,
you know?
To my father.
Hmm?
He doesn't need a reason
to kill people like you.
He needs a reason not to.
Does he have one?
(phone buzzing)
That's fucking confusin'.
Hello?
Alexei: Do you have White Death's son?
What, you mean this dickhead
with the silly face tattoos?
Yeah, he's sat right here.
And the briefcase?
Yes, of course,
I've got the case.
Alexei: You will both
deboard at Kyoto station.
(muffled) Damn it!
Then your business with him
will be concluded.
(phone line beeping)
(chiming over speakers)
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
It was just here.
Well, it's not anymore.
We need to find the person
who took that case.
Ladybug: Maybe you're right.
Maybe my luck
is starting to turn.
(chiming over speakers)
(man speaking Japanese
over speakers)
(grunts)
♫  Social reject, isolated  ♫
(over earbud) ♫  come close  ♫
(Kimura groans)
♫  Suffocate me  ♫
♫  unlocked my front door  ♫
♫  I want more  ♫
♫  face down
my mouth on the fucking floor  ♫
(Kimura groaning)
♫  Hurt me, I'll hurt back  ♫
♫  just like this
just like that...  ♫
You.
Yes.
Me.
(music continues muffled)
But you are yuichi kimura.
And you came here
to kill me.
(Kimura sighs)
My parents call me...
(speaking Russian)
That means "little prince."
Obviously, they wanted a boy.
You're going to want
to hear the whole story,
or you'll be very...
Very sorry.
(phone buzzing)
(whispering)
It's the hospital.
Hang on.
Hi.
Yes, you can see the boy now.
Good. If you don't hear
from me every ten minutes
or if I don't answer this phone
when you call...
I want you to go in there
and kill...
I'm sorry,
what's your boy's name again?
Wataru.
Right. Right.
Kill wataru.
(scoffs)
Aren't we glad we waited?
We got his son.
That was our job.
Our job was to come back
with his son
and his $10 million.
Three words describe
our situation right now.
Do you know what they are?
Sure do: Saved his son.
Hmm?
Family's more important
than money, right?
Do you honestly not know
who the White Death is?
Yeah, I know the White Death.
You just told me
five minutes ago.
He cuts off arms, puts them...
Why do I even bother
forwarding you the briefings?
I do not know.
(sighs heavily)
The Japanese underworld
used to be ruled
by a man named minegishi.
(man singing in Japanese)
Now, minegishi
was one brutal bastard.
But he was old-school, you know?
Tradition and loyalty
was all that mattered to him.
When you were in, you were in.
You were like family.
He treated you like
you were one of his own.
Then out of the blue comes this
6-foot-fucking-6 geezer
from Russia.
Whispers that he was exiled from
the Russian mafia
or that he was ex-kgb.
No one really knows the truth.
(grunting)
But what is known
is this Russian...
(grunting)
Worked his way up the ranks.
Bit by bit, kill by kill.
(yelling)
And very, very fucking quickly
became one of minegishi's
closest advisors.
And those loyal to him said,
"hold your horses.
This geezer ain't
the full ticket.
He ain't to be trusted.
He's dangerous," they said.
"A modern plague," they said.
"A White Death."
(screaming)
So, sure enough,
they were right.
He made his own alliance.
(explosion)
(screaming)
His own gang.
♫  ♫
(men screaming)
(swords slicing)
And what'd he do?
Stabbed him in the back.
I mean, metaphorically.
Blew his fucking brains out,
didn't he?
(gun cylinder spinning)
♫  Stabbed with a star  ♫
(clicks)
♫  the hammer is on us  ♫
♫  we'll live through the dark  ♫
♫  it's evel knievel  ♫
♫  it's got to be ours...  ♫
He wiped the name minegishi
off the face of the earth
in one single night.
And made an empire
worthy of the White Death.
(gunshot)
(song ends)
(inhales sharply)
(exhales)
So, let me put this bluntly.
There's this soulless
psychotic leader
with the largest criminal
organization on the planet
shoved right inside
our fucking ass cheeks.
That motherfucker's definitely
a diesel, then, isn't he?
If you mention Thomas
the tank engine one more time,
I'm gonna shoot you
in the fucking face.
Okay, okay,
if-if he's such a badass,
how come he hired
two random operators
instead of getting his son
back himself? Mm-mm.
'Cause if you actually
read the briefings,
you'd know that he had a wife.
What, he had a wife?
Yes.
She was the most important
thing in his life,
and she died.
(machine flat lining)
Drunk driving accident
or some shit.
(tires squealing)
And now he's at the compound
and he ain't left since.
An unnamed locomotive
might say there's a lesson
to be learned.
Listen, and he didn't hire
two random operators, lemon.
No, he asked for the best.
He asked for the two responsible
for the Bolivia job.
(chain saw buzzing)
(Tangerine grunting)
(sighs)
(thunder crashing)
Tangerine: He asked for pros
who wouldn't fuck up.
Three words, lemon.
We are...
Fucked.
(whooshing)
What do you want?
People think that
I'm just some young girl.
Someone's future wife, or...
(scoffs)
Future mother.
But I'm not in
someone else's story.
You're all in mine.
The fuck does that
have to do with me?
You work for the most
feared boss in the city;
The White Death.
Oh, deny it all you want.
But you work for someone
who works for someone else,
et cetera, et cetera,
and it all falls under
the same person.
You delivered a briefcase
two days ago
to one of the White Death's
associates...
(camera shutter clicking)
And I saw my opportunity.
Follow the case
and find the White Death.
Don't know what you think
I can do for you.
Oh, that is my favorite part
of the story.
You're going to kill him for me.
How the fuck am I
going to kill the White Death?
You'll see.
Oh, look at that.
We are right on schedule.
Sit back, relax a little bit.
You look so tense.
(Momonga Chef speaking Japanese
on TV)
(Momonga on TV) Momomon.
♫  ♫
We rescued his fucking son, huh?
We find the fucker
who took the briefcase,
make things right,
be like it never happened.
Never happened.
(inhales deeply)
You still got that vest on ya?
Oh, no, vests give you
a false sense of security.
You might, like,
get shot in the neck.
Yeah, it also stops you from
getting shot in the chest,
but I guess you missed that
episode of Thomas, did ya?
I really must've, because
that sounds dark as shit.
Nut up or shut up, bruv.
(punk rock version)
♫  I'm forever blowing bubbles  ♫
♫  pretty bubbles in the air  ♫
♫  they fly so high  ♫
♫  they nearly reach
the sky...  ♫
Tangerine: Well, so,
slight change of plans.
Ho!
Oh!
(music slows, fades)
First his wife, now his son?
That's a lot of white deaths.
(sighs)
{"La Despedida" by Alejandro
Sanz plays in Spanish}
(clucking)
♫  ♫
I want you to be strong, son.
Do you understand?
Sí.
Be strong.
(song continues in Spanish)
♫  ♫
(grunting)
(howling)
(song continues in Spanish)
(inaudible dialogue)
♫  ♫
(man shouts in Spanish)
(song continues in Spanish)
♫  ♫
(guests cheering)
¡Felicidades!
(cheering continues)
(glasses clink)
My heart.
(Wolf shouts in Spanish)
♫  ♫
(inaudible dialogue)
(muffled screaming under music)
(music stops)
(people screaming)
(coughing, retching)
(violent retching)
No!
(distant howling)
(phone rings)
Find me The Son of a bitch who did this.
{"La Despedida" by Alejandro
Sanz resumes playing}
♫  ♫
(song continues in Spanish)
(grunting)
(music stops)
(breathing heavily)
You lucky son of a bitch.
You stabbed me?
(Wolf yelling)
You ruined my life.
I don't even know you!
(Wolf yelling)
I come here for revenge.
The assassin
who killed El saguaro
killed my wife.
(grunts)
But fate made this a two for one special.
Ooh!
(grunts)
(choking)
Can we just
take a time-out here?
Talk this out?
I will never stop
coming for you.
What?
Run as far as you like.
I will find you.
Why?
And I will ruin your life
the way you ruined mine.
Dude, I don't even know you!
(both grunt)
(grunts)
(pants)
(groans)
(panting)
My heart.
(bones crack)
(Ladybug gasps)
What the...?
Wow.
Really?
Let this be a lesson
in the toxicity of anger.
Venezuela, Uruguay,
Barcelona.
(clattering)
(sighs)
(whispering)
Who are you?
Mmm.
(grunts)
(chiming over speakers)
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
(grunts)
(woman continues speaking
Japanese over speakers)
(woman over speakers) All passengers;
We'll make a brief stop
at shin-Yokohama...
Lemon: All right, mate, try these.
Tangerine: Huh?
They're them Momonga glasses.
Tangerine: The fuck is a Momonga?
(female Momonga singers)
♫  Momomon!  ♫
Comes on after Thomas
every Thursday. Okay.
Oh, sh...
Okay.
It's good.
Just like that.
He should look asleep, you know.
There, like that.
Like that? Right.
(crunching)
Uh...
(sighs)
Mmm.
Wasabi.
(chiming over speakers)
We gotta make sure he doesn't
step a foot off this train.
You see the case,
deal with whoever has it.
All right, how do I do that?
Talk to him,
or, like, talk to him?
I don't know,
why don't you tell him
about the story
about how Gordon met Percy
and how Percy's now bleeding
from his fucking eye sockets!
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
He means kill him.
(woman over speakers)
All passengers;
We'll make a brief stop
at shin-Yokohama.
Fuck. Damn it.
(man speaking Japanese
over speakers)
Well, excuse me.
You are fuckin' excused.
(woman gasps)
Arigatou.
(cartoon voices singing
in Japanese over speakers)
Konnichiwa.
(Lemon sighs)
(helicopter passing overhead)
Joburg.
(gunshot echoes)
(Momonga mascot speaking
Japanese)
(high-pitched squeaking)
(grunts)
I'm sorry, buddy.
(high-pitched grunting)
(grunts) Give...
Give it!
(squeaking)
(high-pitched yelp)
(Ladybug grunts)
(high-pitched grunt)
Ah... shit balls.
That wasn't a minute.
(Ladybug sighs)
(sighs)
(phone beeps)
I missed my stop.
Maria: Why?
Because god hates me.
No, she doesn't.
Do you still have the case?
Yeah, I stashed it.
Get off at the next stop.
Ah, it sounds so easy
when you say it.
Does the name El cigarillo
mean anything to you?
♫  ♫
El saguaro?
The cartel boss?
Yeah, why does that sound
so familiar?
He was in the wedding
you infiltrated in Mexico.
Tequila?
You were the cocktail server.
(timer ticking)
(timer dings)
The groom.
I knew I recognized that guy.
I'm really good with faces.
Wait, what guy?
Sorry. Be right back.
The guy who stabbed me.
I spilled wine on his suit.
He's dead now.
Maria: You killed the wolf?
It was an accident.
I'm really gonna have to process
my part in the incident
on Monday.
Shit. Fuck! No.
Maria: Shit fuck what?
Ladybug: Remember those
two wackos from the Bolivia job?
Killed all those people?
Maria: The twins?
Yeah, I'm not so sure
they're twins.
Stop it.
Everyone knows they're twins.
Well, one of them is walking
towards me right now.
I think I saw the other
on the platform.
- Maria: Well, now we know
- Occupied.
who the owners of the case are.
(whispering) See, this is
exactly what I'm talkin' about.
We have to have a hard
discussion about the caliber
of people we are surrounding
ourselves with.
Maria: (whispering) Why are
we whispering?
(phone buzzing)
(sighs)
(phone beeps)
Hello.
Alexei: The white
death would like to know
why you stepped off train.
Tangerine: Wanted some fresh air.
Alexei: Your orders
were to stay on the train.
I didn't realize
I was gettin' a babysitter
to come cut my bollocks.
I'm a professional.
We're making sure the case...
(train whistle toots)
And his son are perfectly safe.
Can I please go do my job now?
If something has gone wrong...
Oh, very kind of you.
Thank you very much.
(phone beeps)
Fuck me! Jesus Christ.
It's very rude,
talking on the phone,
on the train. In Japan.
This rude enough for ya,
ya fucking prick?
Shove that fuckin' hat
up your fuckin' asshole,
you hear me?
(mouthing)
Fuck this job.
I knew we should've got
an upgrade, fuck all.
I beg your pardon, sorry. I...
(inhales deeply)
Wasn't aware there was a
young lady present. Apologize.
Yeah, you didn't happen
to see someone
come by with
a silver briefcase, did ya?
There's a little train sticker
by the handle.
(inhales)
Actually, yeah.
Um, a man with black framed
glasses had it.
He went that way.
(breathes deeply)
Thank you, love.
Tangerine: That fucking bastard.
Come on.
(phone buzzing)
Lemon: "Guy in black
glasses. Stop him."
Hi.
There's a gun under this...
(Lemon shushing)
(quietly)
Whoa. This is the quiet car.
Gotta use your small
inside voice in here, son.
(whispering) There's a
gun underneath this table
pointed right at you,
so I would...
I can't really hear
what you're saying.
There's a gun...
(woman shushing)
(chuckling)
I'm just fuckin' with you, mate.
(chuckles)
It's been a long time
since Johannesburg.
(helicopter whirring)
(dog barking)
Yeah. Who the fuck are you?
Really?
You don't remember me?
(helicopter passing overhead)
You look like every white
homeless man I've ever seen.
Okay.
Well, I have something
I believe you're looking f...
Really? You don't remember me?
I'm sorry, mate.
Huh? I remember Johannesburg,
but I don't remember you.
All right?
You shot me.
(grunts)
I shoot a lot of people.
You shot me twice.
Ow!
Well, you also have
a shoot able face.
I know you're
black framed glasses.
The cheeky fucker
who took our briefcase.
Yes. Yes, I am.
Hmm.
You know, I've done
a lot of personal work
since joburg.
Oh.
I've forgiven, I've moved on.
I've learned that
with any potential conflict
there's an opportunity
for growth,
a path to a peaceful outcome.
Prince: Interesting.
Kimura: Who is that?
I have no idea.
How did you know that was there?
(grunts, sighs)
Didn't I mention?
I've always been lucky.
(loud clank)
It was then that I took a long,
hard look into the mirror.
And you know what?
(Lemon exhales sharply)
Buddy, I didn't like what I saw.
Nope. Nada.
Lemon: Mm.
Until I did.
You know?
Mm.
Between us now sits a wall.
Lemon: Mm-hmm.
But it's an illusion.
For within every wall, uh,
awaits a window...
Oh, wait, it's-it's a door.
Real quick, um,
every day is a fucking headache
with you, innit?
Right.
(clears throat)
You and your partner...
Look, I'm lemon, he's tangerine.
Okay, lemon... like the fruit?
Blessings.
Mm.
What's your plan here?
Here's the plan.
I give you back your case,
you don't kill me.
You give your case
to your employer,
he doesn't kill you.
You're alive, I'm alive,
everyone's happy.
Win-win, don't you think?
How do you know
whoever hired you
won't kill you
for failing your job?
Lose-lose. No happy.
Man, I just want
to get off this train,
go see a zen garden
and some shit, you know?
I'd like to accept your offer.
Great. But then you
went and killed someone.
Didn't you?
How did you know...?
Wasn't exactly subtle.
Uh, it-it was an accident.
(chuckling)
Tragic.
Bizarre, even.
That's a...
Cool story, bro, but, um,
I think you had your own plans
of getting out of here
with that case.
No, no.
Pinning a body on us.
Hoping the White Death
is so busy
cuttin' off our arms instead
of cuttin' off our fingers.
It's like Thomas
the Tank Engine always says;
"Simple is better."
The kids' show?
Yes, the fucking kid...
Man...
I learned everything
about people from Thomas.
Everything.
Really?
That's how I can read
people like you so well,
and you are a diesel.
Huh.
I am not a diesel.
You're the diesel-est diesel
that ever fuckin' diesel-ed
not even close.
That I've ever seen
in my life, man.
'Cause diesels bluff,
they go too far.
Man, I'm trying to get diesels
out of my life, you know?
If there was a gun
under this table, yeah,
I'd be as dead
as that kid over there.
Hmm?
(gasps, muffled shout)
(grunting)
(groans)
Ooh.
(Lemon grunts)
(shushing)
(scoffs quietly)
Mm-mm. Uh-uh.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
No-nope.
(grunts)
(both grunting)
You mother...
(both straining)
Oh!
(grunting)
Have the courage to listen.
(yells)
(shushes)
(panting)
(hums, whistles)
(chuckles)
(groans quietly)
(yelling)
(growling)
(inhales sharply)
Come on, joburg.
No.
Shot number three.
(both straining)
(gasps)
♫  ♫
(music playing)
(high-pitched chuckle)
Tangerine: No, no,
no. I ain't got the time
or the Patience,
let alone the interest.
(low) Fucking hell.
(high-pitched squeaking)
Are you following me?
Stop!
(high-pitched squeal)
Asshole.
(high-pitched) Ow.
(grunting)
(choking)
(cries out)
(grunts)
(gasping rapidly)
(woman shushes)
(whispering)
I'll call the conductor!
Eat a bag of dicks, lady.
(woman gasps)
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm-I'm working on it.
(whimpers quietly)
(fizzing)
(sighs)
(grunts)
I'm not a diesel,
you're a diesel.
♫  ♫
(phone buzzes)
(phone clicks)
(grunts)
Ow!
(woman shushing)
(whooshing)
(whispering)
There's another body here.
Maria: Of course there is.
Not my fault.
And I believe it's The Son
of the White Death.
Did the twins I.D. you?
Did you hear what I said?
White Death. Death. Death.
(gunshot)
Snatch and grab, my ass.
There's someone else
doing a job on this train.
Maria: The twins. We know that.
Again, not twins.
Loonies but not twins.
(thunder rumbles)
They're here for the kid,
but somebody killed the kid.
(sighs)
The guy with the knife.
Maria: The wolf.
(howling)
He said he came here
for revenge.
He just happened to run into me,
because of course he did.
Now, get this.
The kid was poisoned
in the same way
as El sbarro was at the wedding.
Maria: It's El saguaro.
The same killer?
Yeah.
I'm like MacGyver.
(snake hissing)
Fuck!
(news theme plays)
All of Japan is in terror
.
because a poisonous snake was stolen.
Boom slang snakes
.
have a very strong poison.
Zookeeper: When they bite,
.
it can cause internal bleeding...
and bleeding from holes in the body.
Oh, shit.
Maria: What are you doing?
What's wrong?
Fuck this, man.
Fuck carver.
(door opens)
Shit.
(Lemon groans)
Oh, thank god.
For a minute there...
Jesus Christ,
you had a bit of a bosh, pal.
(Lemon muttering groggily)
Tangerine: All right.
Five stations to Kyoto.
Better get tickety-boo.
(Tangerine mutters)
Would you describe me as someone
who lives in perpetual anxiety?
Maria: No, no.
Ah, fuck nuts.
And if it wasn't clear,
I meant "yes."
The conductor.
I don't have a ticket.
Not sure that's
your biggest concern.
You don't understand.
This guy's like
criss-fuckin'-angel.
He pops up everywhere.
He slows me down,
tangerine catches me,
I am dead.
Dead. Dead...
Hold on.
Hey, bro.
(whistles)
Want to make an easy 200 bucks?
Is this like a...
Like a sex thing?
Nope.
(chuckles) Oh, okay.
I was... I was kidding.
Uh, yeah, what's up?
What do you need, bro?
(door whirring, thumping)
(clanging)
(toy squeaks)
Toy: Momomon!
(gunshot)
(exhales heavily)
All right, game's up, big boy.
Where is the case?
Tell me, and I promise
I'll only shoot you enough...
Whoa, whoa, um...
Is-is this the sex stuff?
(firecrackers popping)
(people exclaiming)
(man shouting)
Twat!
Shit.
I-I do love an accent.
(people murmuring)
(people exclaiming)
Come on.
Oops.
Picture it.
Picture what?
Well, the man.
Watching your son.
I wonder how he'll do it.
Maybe a pillow to the face.
Or maybe something clever.
Like an air bubble in the iv.
(Kimura sighs)
No, no. You hold onto it.
The innocent young girl act
doesn't really get you very far
if you're holding a loaded gun.
(phone buzzing)
(Kimura speaks Japanese)
Put it on speaker.
(phone beeps)
- Father.
- Yuichi?
Why did you leave the hospital?
Be honest.
Who's there with you?
I found out who pushed Wataru
off that roof.
Did you go to the authorities?
I wanted to handle it myself.
My son.
You can't control
what fate has in store for us.
Father.
I'm sorry.
(phone beeps)
Prince: We're not finished.
You're going to sit here
and you're going to go through
every combination
until you open up that case.
Kid, that could take f...
No, no. It won't.
I'd start with the low numbers.
Just a thought.
(Kimura stammers)
♫  ♫
(grunts)
Fuck me!
(gasping)
There he is.
He-he got by me.
Yeah. Yeah, me, too.
(Lemon groans)
Tangerine: Well, I
guess our best option now
is, uh, bring the White Death
the man who killed his son.
Yeah, but glasses didn't do it.
I could give a rat's ass.
No, I'm telling you.
I read him.
He's not the type, mate.
Uh, I'll tell you what,
do you like your arms?
You know I like my arms.
Well, then someone's got to
take the blame, don't they?
(phone buzzing)
That's you or me?
You or me?
(chiming over speakers)
Shit, that asshole
stole my phone.
You kidding.
And my gun, Lucille.
Oh, come on.
That's my favorite gun.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck about...
(phone beeps)
Right, what?
Alexei: Step off the
train at the next stop
with the briefcase and The Son.
Well, hang on,
didn't we say Kyoto?
You will still depart at Kyoto.
The White Death
wants to make sure
you are being honest
about situation.
Well, this is a waste
of our t...
(phone line beeping)
All right, all right.
We just have to prove
we have a case we don't have
and a live son
instead of a dead one.
What are you thinking?
The ol' punch and Judy?
The ol' punch and Judy.
{"Kill Me Pretty"
by Tamio Okuda intro playing}
(gun racking rhythmically
to music)
(tamio okuda vocalizing)
♫  Kill me, kill me
kill me pretty  ♫
♫  kill me, kill me
(song continues in Japanese)
You were all told
to exit the train.
Tangerine: Yeah?
Well, unlike you,
I'm a professional.
I wanted to make sure
it weren't some yakuza trap,
but clearly not.
It's some fuckin'
'80s dance-off, innit?
Where is your twin?
Tangerine?
I'm tangerine.
Lemon's keepin' the case safe.
And the White Death's son?
Yeah, he's there.
(window squeaking)
Lemon: Wave to your
fuckin' fans, Princess.
He's a fuckin' happy chappy,
isn't he?
But, uh, I've gotta pop
on the train,
you know, ten seconds left,
so ta-ra.
We'll stick to the plan,
depart in Kyoto.
Do us a favor,
get the fuck off my back,
will ya?
(musical chiming)
♫  Yeah...  ♫
(whooshing)
(sighs heavily)
(breathing heavily)
Okay.
Whoa!
(man speaking Japanese
over speakers)
Lemon: Okay.
(breathes deeply)
Okay.
(door opens)
I mean, that couldn't
have gone better.
Yeah, let's hope they buy it.
We need to find
that glasses twat,
like, right to the fuck now.
(sniffs, grunts loudly)
I'm gonna go up, you go down,
double back when you're done.
If you see him,
fucking deal with him.
Yeah?
Yeah.
(sighs heavily)
Up is...?
That way. Towards Tokyo.
Right. Departing trains
are always moving down.
And, look, be careful.
Something else is
going on here. Yeah?
Yeah, I still feel like
there's a diesel lurking about.
I swear to god, what'd I say?
What did I say?
I said I'll fucking
shoot you in...
Shoot me in the face. Yeah.
That's right.
Thomas still taught me
how to see people,
read them for real.
Yeah.
And I'm never wrong, am I?
No.
Glasses, he is not our guy.
Okay.
You shoot first and come up
with the answers later.
(water bottle sloshing)
(sniffs)
I always do.
And, lemon?
Yeah, man?
You be careful, too.
(clicks tongue)
Oh, man,
when this train's a-rockin',
don't come a-knockin', right?
(whooshing)
(frantically muttering
in Japanese)
♫  ♫
(continues muttering)
(breathing heavily)
(song continues in Japanese)
♫  I'll make you cry  ♫
♫  I make a girl cry
make a girl cry  ♫
(song continues in Japanese)
♫  I'll make you cry  ♫
♫  ♫
Ladybug: Ah, seven more
minutes and I am off this train.
Maria: Are you hiding in a bathroom?
Yeah. Have you tried
these smart toilets?
They're... a pleasure
to the senses.
If I had one in the chamber,
I would rock this bad boy
right now.
Boundaries.
We need boundaries.
(Kimura speaks quietly
in Japanese)
(latches click)
Holy shit.
(door opens)
Whoa there.
(laughs)
Oh, look at that.
I knew my luck
would rub off on you.
(sighs)
Kimura: Fuck.
What the fuck are you doing?
I am doing the same thing
that I did to the gun
in your hand.
(trilling beeps)
I'm just making things
interesting.
I'm hedging my bets,
you could say.
Fuck.
Prince: If the gun doesn't
kill him, the case will.
This thing could have blown up
in my hand at any point.
Prince: No. No.
It's inert unless you fire it.
But don't fire it, you know
what I mean? (chuckles)
Unlike what I put
in this briefcase here.
This is very...
(beeping)
Well, this is not inert at all.
This is...
(Kimura groans)
Did you know
that there have been
31 attempts
on the White Death's life
from within
his own organization?
Each one,
he executed
with their own weapon.
Do you see
what I'm getting at here?
(Kimura grunts quietly)
Kimura,
I brought you here to fail.
You push my son off a roof.
Right.
Bring me to this train,
frame me as an assassin,
here to kill the White Death,
and use my gun
that will blow up in his face?
Very good.
Very, very good.
It's a stupid plan.
It is...
A brilliant plan.
(automated voice
speaks Japanese)
(knocking on door)
Ladybug: Occupied.
Maria: You remember that mob surgeon
that died mid-heart operation?
(beeps)
Ladybug: Yeah, he had a stroke, right?
No, that was the official
cover. He was poisoned.
The assassin goes by the name
of the hornet.
(screaming)
Oh, my god!
(beeps)
(automated voice
speaks Japanese)
Maria: He used boom slang snake venom.
It congeals the blood,
making you bleed
out of every orifice.
If the antidote isn't
administered within 30 seconds,
you're dead.
Fun fact; The same poison
that was used on...
El sagardo.
It's El saguaro.
What is the hornet doing
on this train?
Well, whatever deal was made,
it wasn't done through
the normal channels.
There's something else
going on here.
(knocking on door)
(woman in Japanese)
It's still occupied, lady.
(scoffs)
The wolf must have figured out
who the hornet is,
came here for revenge
for his wife, his boss,
came here to whack the hornet.
Maria: Oh, my god, did
you just say "whack"?
I did. I'm bringing it back.
No, it needs to stay
where it was.
If I can figure out
who the hornet is,
I can give him
to lemon and tangerine
so they don't whack me.
Really?
Se... you see what I did there?
You're really proud
of yourself, aren't you?
(knocking on door)
Geez, they're usually
so polite here.
Lady, I'm so...
(beeping rapidly)
Oh.
That's cool.
Come here, you...
(cries out)
Bastard!
(both straining)
Come here,
you-you dirty fucking scum!
(grunting)
♫  ♫
Ah, you bastard.
(grunting)
Ladybug: Wait-wait-wait-wait-wait.
I know who killed the kid.
I couldn't give a rat's ass.
Where's my fucking case?
♫  ♫
(door opens)
(song stops)
(woman speaks Japanese)
Yeah.
Oh.
(speaking Japanese)
Oh, I'm so sorry. Excuse me.
(rustling)
(speaking Japanese)
Oh, no, thank you.
We're okay.
Oh, I-I would love
a bottle of water.
(bottles clinking)
(speaking Japanese)
You know what? Do you have,
um, anything sparkling?
With bubbles?
Hai.
That's the one. Thank y...
Domo a rig a to.
(woman speaks Japanese)
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Bro, I just remembered
I gave all my money
to that guy to wear
my h-hat and glasses.
Could you?
(Ladybug gulps, sighs)
How much for the bottle
of water, love?
(speaks Japanese)
(Ladybug sighs heavily)
Oh, there. No, you're welcome.
(speaking Japanese)
Yeah. A thousand yen.
That's ten quid for
that bottle of water, mate.
Mmm.
(speaking Japanese)
Mm.
Ta-ra.
Domo a rig a to.
Mmm.
You sure you don't want
to talk this out?
Not particularly, no.
(sighs)
Okay.
(song resumes)
(Tangerine yelling)
You fucking bastard! Fucker!
Come here, you little fuck!
(Ladybug grunting)
(straining)
I know who killed the kid.
Tangerine: Yeah?
Where the fuck is he, then?
He's on this train.
Oh, well, that narrows it down,
then, don't it?
(grunts)
Let go! Get off!
(train horn blows)
(bells clanging)
(whooshing)
(grunts)
(grunting)
(strained grunting)
(phone buzzing)
You gonna get that?
No.
Ladybug: You probably ought to get that.
(buzzing continues)
It could be important.
Oh, okay, maybe it's important.
Fucking hell.
Come here.
(Ladybug groans)
(phone beeps)
Yeah, what do you want?
Alexei: The White Death
says to get off at next stop
holding the briefcase
or he will kill everyone
on that train.
Okay, yeah, I can make it,
but, uh, lemon, he's a little
tied up right now.
Both of you this time,
with the case, or everyone dies.
Fuckin' paranoid, this lot.
You don't happen to have
the case on you, do ya?
No.
Yeah, I don't think
I'd reach lemon in time anyway.
You still got his phone.
Do you have a gun on ya?
Don't like 'em.
Well...
(chiming over speakers)
Game's up, mate.
For what it's worth, you seem
like a right fucking asshole
and I'm glad you're gonna
fucking die with me.
That's nice.
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
(groans)
Just curious.
Yeah?
Do they even know
what lemon looks like?
Wow.
You two do look like twins, huh?
Yeah, okay.
We got the case, now what?
You still take the train
to Kyoto station.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Okay. We can do that.
Wonderful.
Alexei: Hey.
Have you opened the case?
Tangerine: No, of course not.
Do you know what? I never asked
for the combination.
You know what I mean?
Keep it safe that way.
Ladybug: Yeah.
(bad English accent)
So no one gets greedy.
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
(musical chiming)
♫  ♫
(whooshing)
(groans)
I know, I know.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I-I have this bad luck thing,
and I hit the thing
oh, is that what you call it?
And it went... (groans)
So why the... what was that?
Why did you even bother trying?
I was trying to sell it.
I was selling it.
Well, I don't think
they were in the market
for fucking dildos
and pantyhose, were they?
Ah, but...
They were buying it.
They were...
(groans)
I was... I had 'em.
(sighs)
Kimura: You proved you're
smarter than everyone.
You've won, kid.
Please.
Please, kid.
Call your man.
I'll do what you want.
Just...
Leave my son alone.
Your son.
Do you know how easy it was
to get him to follow me
up onto that roof?
Didn't think it would
take you three hours
to even realize
your son was missing.
You're a terrible father,
and your son is going to pay
for all the mistakes
that you've made.
You don't know anything
about life.
How hard it is.
You're just...
Some spoiled girl
who breaks their toys
when mommy says
she has to pick up.
(door opens)
Sorry. Pardon me,
I don't mean to interrupt
what's, uh, going on here,
but, uh, you wouldn't happen
to have seen a tiny white prick
with a pair of glasses
come through here, have you?
(sighs)
No.
What about a silver case
with a train sticker
by the handle? You seen that?
It's not ringing any...
Uh, uncle kimura, have you seen
a silver briefcase
with the, uh, train...
Did you say "train sticker
by the handle"?
Yeah. On the handle...
That's unique.
It had a train sticker.
No, I haven't seen
anything like that.
I think I'd remember.
Hmm.
(shakes bottle)
I'm s...
"Uncle kimura"?
Yeah.
Y... right.
Are you okay? That's...
(coughs quietly)
Oh, yeah.
Never shave on a bullet train,
you know what they say.
Well, couldn't hurt
to ask, you know?
I'm just gonna keep
following him.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, no, it's all right.
Go for it.
Pardon me, "uncle kimura."
You guys, take care.
Just one thing, though.
Uh, most people...
Most people assume "suitcase,"
you know, 'cause it's a train,
overnight and all.
But you...
You said "briefcase."
I never said "briefcase."
I think...
(exhales)
I found my diesel.
You know what's waiting
for us in Kyoto.
Tangerine: Mm-hmm.
(chiming over speakers)
We should just get off
this train. Now.
If you think I'm stepping off
this train without lemon
or the case,
you must be mistaken.
Okay. Well, the case
is in the first-class lounge.
It's behind the bar,
it's in a trash can.
It's yours.
Me, I'm getting off.
I'm gonna go find a temple
and reevaluate my choices
or something.
Ooh, that sounds very lovely,
but here's the deal.
I still need a fall guy.
(chiming over speakers)
(sighs)
Shit.
(sputters lips)
You need a fall guy.
Yeah.
No, I understand.
I-I get it.
(both sighing heavily)
It's a bit of
a conundrum, really,
'cause, you know, I'm thinking,
"do I hand him back in one piece
"or do I chop you up
into little pieces
and stuff you inside
a fucking Momomon or not?"
That's what's going through
my head right now.
Hmm.
Or...
Oh, what?
You got a better idea, do ya?
You know, before us now
is just a wall,
but it's an illusion, man.
It's a construct.
You know, 'cause within
that wall sits a window.
A window of opportunity.
Damn it, it's a door.
It's...
(watch ticking)
Within that wall is a door.
I'm finding it very hard
to follow this story.
My point is,
that door is closing.
(grunts)
(musical chiming)
(laughing triumphantly)
(yelling)
Now the only question is;
Which one is the diesel,
which one is the duck?
"The duck"?
It's a kids' show.
Thomas the train engine.
Close.
Thomas the tank engine.
Please, mister.
This... this man,
he kidnapped me,
and he said that he's going
to hold me for ransom.
(quiet sobs)
I'm sorry. I get captivated
by white-girl tears.
Bravo.
Common sense tells me
that this old, shaky geezer here
is the one in charge,
but I'm really good
at reading people,
and something tells me
you are just not fucking right.
(smacks lips)
So... let's see here.
I mean, I can't shoot you both.
Then I get no answers.
You know what, how about this?
I'm sure you'll love this.
We're gonna play a little game.
Huh? If you want
to play a game,
put both your hands up.
Perfect. I knew
you would like this.
You're gonna close your eyes,
and I'm gonna count to three.
And whichever one of you
is in charge,
you're gonna raise your hand,
and whichever one isn't,
you point at who is.
Now, if you both
raise your hands
or you both point at each other,
I know you're both liars,
and the truth ain't in ya,
and then I'll fucking
shoot you both. Ready?
You-you said
you couldn't kill us both.
You'd get no answers.
I did say that, didn't I?
Yes.
Sometimes you gotta shoot first
and come up with answers later.
One.
Prince: Or if I don't answer
this phone when you call...
Lemon: Two.
Prince: Kill wataru.
Lemon: Three.
(gunshot echoing)
(muffled breathing)
(gasps)
{"Tokiniwa Haha No Naiko No
Youni" by Carmen Maki plays}
Am I dreaming?
(carmen maki singing
in Japanese)
♫  ♫
(Kimura groaning)
(exhales)
Sorry, mate.
Not your lucky day.
(groaning)
(sighs)
Prince: I have a wire i-in my bag,
and I-I think
that we could use it
to-to lock the door
from the outside.
It was so scary.
He said that if I didn't
do what he said,
or if I yelled or anything,
that he would do awful,
awful things to me.
Then why didn't you
use this, then?
(stammers)
Yeah, he kidnapped ya and, uh,
gave you his gun to hold, right?
Easy. No, no, no, no.
You see, he... no, um...
I... please.
I don't know how to use a gun.
I don't know.
Please.
Fuck me. You are fucking...
You are really good.
You sure you didn't study?
I mean, you're not even afraid
and your lip's quivering.
That's a tear. That is really
authentic, mate, like...
(clicks tongue)
You're the diesel.
I gotta kill ya. (laughs)
I'm just...
Please, I'm just a kid.
Please.
How do you do that?!
I'm not...
(gun cocks)
It's really unbelievable.
Please. Please.
You...
You are...
(mumbles)
(pants)
I got, um...
It's fucking...
You stay right there.
Did you...?
What the fuck is happening?
(panting)
Everyone loves lemons.
(whooshing)
(muffled screaming)
Fucking die!
♫  ♫
I'm glad you enjoyed
the performance.
(groggily)
How did you do that?
I'm not sure.
Just lucky, I guess.
Tell tangerine that...
Tell tangerine...
Tangerine...
He's gone.
Tangerine is gone.
(whooshing)
Getting off this train.
I'm getting that case,
and that's it.
(phone buzzing)
(phone beeps)
Hello?
(The Elder speaking Japanese
over phone)
Uh, it looks like yuichi lost
his phone on the bullet train.
You can pick it up
at Kyoto station, though.
Kyoto...
There's this find my phone app.
(beeping rapidly)
Oh.
Surprisingly accurate.
Bye.
(whooshing)
(groaning quietly)
(sniffs, exhales)
(to self)
God, he's got a great walk.
(sighs)
(beeping)
Ladybug: Mr. Wolf.
So you came to kill the hornet.
(faint howling)
What happened?
(wind blowing, papers rustling)
Are you okay?
Fuck, that thing is hot.
(wind blowing)
(exhales)
(high-pitched)
Momomomo.
♫  ♫
Momomon.
Go.
Mom on.
No. Lea...
Momomon.
(high-pitched squealing)
(The Son choking)
(retching violently)
The pastry chef.
♫  ♫
Oh.
You stole my snake, bitch.
(snake hissing)
That was your...
We should really call
the authorities
'cause someone...
(hornet yells)
(both grunting)
Take that, punk!
Hey, bitch.
(grunting)
One little prick from this,
you know what happens?
Yes.
Your blood congeals,
clogging your veins.
You bleed out of
your fucking eye socket.
I said yes!
(grunts)
Weak-ass bitch.
Stop.
I'm taking that case.
Give it!
(high-pitched yelp)
I was promised my money.
By who?
Don't know. It was all online.
(straining) They said my
money was in the case.
What? Someone paid you
to have the kid killed
with his own ransom?
Wow. That's dark.
That is dark as...
(grunting)
Stop!
(Ladybug groans)
The hornet stings, bitch!
Lady, you can have the case.
Oh, but you've seen
my face, bitch.
(gasps)
Thirty seconds before the venom
does its thing.
♫  ♫
(gasps)
(grunts)
(neck cracks)
Oh.
You bitch.
Oh, shit, man.
Do you have a backup?
(straining)
What do you think, bitch?
(choking)
Oh, shit, man.
(gasping)
You don't have another one?
You gotta be better prepared.
(coughing)
I'm mansplaining,
I'm mansplaining again.
I'm sorry. It didn't...
Uh...
Can I get you something?
(grunting)
(clattering)
Uh... you don't seem like
a religious person.
(gasping)
Water? Would you...
Would you like some water?
(gasping)
No?
You want a blanket?
You want me to hold your hand?
(choking)
(sighs)
Karma is a bitch.
(inhales deeply)
(wire clatters)
♫  ♫
(somber version)
♫  I'm forever blowing bubbles  ♫
♫  pretty bubbles in the air  ♫
♫  they fly so high  ♫
♫  nearly reach the sky  ♫
♫  then like my dreams  ♫
♫  they fade and die  ♫
♫  fortune's always hiding  ♫
♫  I've looked everywhere  ♫
♫  I'm forever  ♫
♫  blowing bubbles  ♫
(breath quavering)
♫  Pretty bubbles  ♫
(clears throat)
♫  In the air  ♫
♫  pretty bubbles  ♫
♫  in the air  ♫
(song fades)
(whooshing)
(bag crinkling)
Maria: Talk to me.
It's my bad luck.
It's bad luck on acid.
I-I-I-I gotta get off
this train.
Do you have the case?
Yes.
Are you lying on the ground
in the fetal position?
(sighs)
I'm not on the ground.
You need to get up.
How do you always know
what I'm doing?
Because I know you.
I could journal.
I should journal.
Ladybug. Ladybug.
Man.
Breathe. Deep breaths.
We're almost there.
You just need to get up.
Right.
{"Sweet Thang" by Shuggie Otis
playing}
(exhales heavily)
(inhaling deeply)
(blowing air)
♫  ooh, ooh, ooh, baby  ♫
♫  sweet thang  ♫
(song fades)
(phone buzzing)
(beeps)
White Death: You have
been lying to me, my friend.
(grunts thoughtfully)
Well, cat's out of the bag
now, innit?
You were responsible
for keeping my son safe.
For keeping my money safe.
You know, I-I don't know
a thing or two
about being a parent,
but you know what I would do,
being that it's your son
and your money?
I'd stop crying
about your dead wife,
get off your fucking lazy ass,
come here
and finish the job yourself.
But as we're having a bit
of a heart-to-heart,
got a couple things to tell ya.
Your son's a complete bell end
and fuckin' deserves
to be bleeding
out of his eye sockets.
And as for your case,
I haven't seen it since Tokyo.
And I hope someone's
fuckin' found it,
put it all on red and having
a fuckin' wonderful time.
I will meet you
at Kyoto station.
Oh, how wonderful.
I can't fucking wait.
I want to look into your eyes
when I kill you
and your brother.
My brother.
(crowd on TV) ♫  I'm forever
blowing bubbles  ♫
♫  pretty bubbles
in the air...  ♫
(man on TV) West Ham
have taken it!
West Ham one, Chelsea nil.
(exhales)
Morning rush hour's rolling in
quite nicely.
Uh, what's your plan, mate?
You gonna fuckin' waltz up here
and blow my brains out
in front of the whole fuckin'
carriage of witnesses?
There is no one left
on that train.
I know.
I bought every ticket
until the end of the line.
(phone line beeping)
Tangerine: Oi.
You.
I know you.
You're that girl, aren't ya?
Prince: Oh, my god.
Yeah, I never forget a face, me.
I'm so happy to see you.
Please help me.
Um, there's this man,
and he was holding me hostage.
He was wearing glasses,
and he killed my uncle.
And he also killed
this other man who,
I don't know,
he just kept talking about,
uh, uh, uh,
t-Thomas the trains and...
Tank engine.
Uh, yeah, right. Exactly.
But he killed both of them,
and then he said
he was going to get away
with some sort of money.
I don't know.
I'm sorry, darling.
I-I beg your pardon.
I don't know
who the fuck you are.
I'm just a girl who was
supposed to get off at nagoya,
and then this man, he...
That was fucking ages ago.
I know, but this man,
he just said
that I could be
a good backup plan
and that a pretty girl
makes a good hostage.
Yeah, well, he ain't
wrong there, but, hey, look.
Keep your fucking knickers on,
all right?
Please just help me.
All right, all right. Calm down.
Get off or do what the fuck
you like. You're free to go.
Thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, yeah.
It's all right. Go on. Take...
Yeah, I don't know
what you're doing here anyway.
Huh.
Are you okay?
Diesel.
The absolutely fucking worst.
Little shit-stirrer.
(breathes heavily)
See, lemon...
god rest his soul,
was the Don,
and he could read people.
See them for who
they really are. What?
He was right.
There's been a diesel
running up and down this train,
causing all sorts
of fucking havoc.
And it was you
the whole fucking time,
you dirty little diesel!
♫  ♫
You made lemon bleed.
And lemon never bleeds.
Oh, my god, mister!
Please help me!
Ladybug.
Please!
Please help me!
Bugger.
You little shit.
Please! What the fuck are
you doing, you bell end?!
You...
Sir! Please!
(gunshot)
(train squealing)
(panting)
Oh.
(grunting)
(strained grunt)
What?
(sputters) Diesel!
(gurgling)
You fucking bell end!
You're a diesel.
What the fuck?
Um...
(quietly) What the fuck?
He said that he was
going to kill you
and blame everything on you.
He also said that
there's someone waiting for us
at Kyoto station.
Someone scary,
who would hurt me.
No one's gonna hurt you.
It's okay.
We're getting off this train.
(sighs)
(clattering)
We make the next stop,
we'll be fine.
(woman speaking Japanese
over speakers)
♫  ♫
(man speaking Japanese
over speakers)
Okay, kid, come o...
Kid, come on.
I can't.
My backpack is stuck.
What?
Leave it. Let's go.
We gotta go, we gotta go.
No. No, I can't.
Right now, young lady!
No.
It's our last chance.
No. No, no, no,
please come back.
(musical chiming)
(sighs) Kid, please.
Prince: I'm scared. I don't want...
to be alone, please.
(sighs)
I got it.
It's not your fault, kid.
It's... it's my luck,
not yours.
You got your whole life
ahead of you.
Make sure you do something
that brings you peace,
'cause everything else
is a pain in the ass.
And if you run into a guy
named carver, he's a dick.
You can tell him I said so.
Um...
I, uh, I...
I took this.
I didn't want to leave it.
The man had it,
and I thought
you could probably use it
to kill whoever's waiting
for us at the end of the line.
You're not going
to let me get hurt.
Be honest.
Who's there with you?
Really?
Right.
Uh, okay, fella.
You're creepin' me out,
so, if you don't mind,
could you just find
another seat,
like, way, way, way down there?
And that way,
I won't have to tell you twice.
(scoffs)
No.
You won't.
(sighs)
(sighs heavily)
Let's just move.
Let me grab your bag.
Ow!
(snake hissing)
(screaming)
(yelling, grunting)
(screams)
Was that a snake?
Would you know where my son is?
(grunting)
(beeps)
(automated voice
speaks Japanese)
Ow. Ow, ow, ow, ow. Ow.
Ow. (grunting)
(water sloshing)
(sputtering)
Ow.
(panting)
(beeps)
(automated voice
speaks Japanese)
Oh, fuck.
(phone buzzing)
(buzzing continues)
Wow. After everything.
(sighs heavily)
You are the person
who pushed my grandson
off the department store roof.
Why?
Your son.
He was going to help me
kill the White Death
at Kyoto station.
And that was the only way
to get him on this train.
The White Death.
That's right.
But he couldn't even do that.
So he's dead.
Just a few cars back.
They are both dead.
(monitors beep rhythmically)
(footsteps echoing)
My grandson
was pushed off a roof.
What makes you think
I would leave him unprotected?
(monitors beep rhythmically)
(grunting, gasping)
♫  ♫
(cries out)
(phone buzzing)
My grandson is safe.
And my son is not dead.
Listen, old man...
(gasps)
The only thing you know
about an old man, young lady,
is that he has survived
much more,
and much worse, than you.
I'll fucking kill him myself.
(door closes)
(grunts softly)
(exhales)
(sighs heavily)
Are you all right?
That?
You're not gonna believe
this coincidence,
but I already got a dose
of antivenom in me today,
so I'm good.
Probably.
The girl...
Her intentions with you
were not honorable.
Yeah.
A blind man could see
you are the one in the dark.
I don't know about a blind man.
She was pretty convincing.
What did you do to her?
I did not need to do anything.
Fate will do what it wills.
(scoffs)
(Ladybug laughs quietly)
Why...
Why do you laugh at fate?
(sighs)
Man, fate for me is
just another word for bad luck.
And that...
(exhales heavily)
That follows me around like...
I don't know, something witty.
My handler calls me ladybug.
She's witty.
Ladybug?
Yeah.
This is very lucky, indeed.
No, she's being ironic.
She...
Ah, never mind.
I'm going to tell you
a story now.
No, I'm good.
It's short.
Really, I'm fine.
No, it's very quick.
No, no.
It's a good story for you,
I think.
I'm cool.
Here we go.
A long time ago,
I made a promise to myself...
that I would provide
for my family
no matter what it cost.
♫  ♫
I had risen to
a highly coveted position
within the minegishi
crime family.
A man raised up
to take my place.
A man from the north.
(man screaming)
(yells)
(groaning)
I asked minegishi
not to trust this man.
Minegishi told me
I had lost my appetite.
He was not wrong.
But neither was I.
(gun cylinder clicking)
♫  ♫
(men yelling)
(yelling)
♫  ♫
(gunshot echoes)
(grunting, panting)
(grunting in pain)
I returned home
and found nothing
except ash and blood.
♫  ♫
(shouting in Japanese)
(grunting)
(speaking Japanese)
(yelling)
The White Death had taken
everything from me.
Almost.
(child coughing)
Yuuichi!
(panting)
Yuuichi.
(grunts)
I went into hiding.
I searched for a way
to strike at the White Death
without endangering
what I had left,
but he remained
forever out of reach.
I did not think
fate would ever give me
a chance to make things right.
Do you know what they call
a ladybug in Japan?
(grunts softly)
Ten to um us hi.
As a boy, I was told
there is a spot on its back
for each of the seven sorrows
of the world.
You see,
ten to um us hi is not lucky.
It holds all the bad luck
so that others
may live in peace.
I-I don't want to hold
the seven sorrows.
Everything that's ever
happened to you
has led you here.
Fate.
Well, that's a shit deal.
At Kyoto station,
the White Death will arrive
on this train.
I will finally be allowed
to make things right.
My son is a few cars up.
If you could escort him
off this train...
Yeah, I don't see
the White Death
letting any of us
off this train.
You let me worry about
the White Death.
Okay.
(inhales deeply)
Mr. Ladybug?
(Ladybug groans)
Your briefcase.
Thank you.
♫  ♫
(whooshing)
(Kimura grunting, groans)
Ladybug: Oh, wow. Oh.
Father.
(panting)
I don't understand.
It is fate, my son.
And Wataru?
He is safe.
(panting)
Well, he seemed like
a decent guy.
He shot me.
Mm, me, too.
Twice.
Still, he had another side
to him...
(gasps)
(yawns loudly)
Wow.
(yawning)
Oh.
(sighs)
Oh, man.
Am I in hell?
(spits, sniffs)
Ah, fuck.
(laughs)
Eh, fuckin' vest, man.
Oh, you drank the water.
(chain jingles)
♫  ♫
Where the fuck is my brother?
{"Five Hundred Miles"
by Song for Memories playing}
♫  ♫
♫  If you missed
the train I'm on  ♫
♫  you will know
that I am gone  ♫
(sniffles)
♫  you can hear  ♫
Aw, man.
♫  The whistle blow  ♫
♫  a hundred miles  ♫
(Lemon sighs)
(chuckles softly)
♫  a hundred miles  ♫
♫  a hundred miles
a hundred miles  ♫
♫  a hundred miles  ♫
you...
♫  You can hear  ♫
(sighs heavily)
♫  The whistle blow  ♫
You were more like Thomas
anyway, right?
♫  A hundred miles  ♫
(Lemon breathes deeply)
(screaming)
♫  Lord, I'm one
lord, I'm two  ♫
♫  lord, I'm three  ♫
(panting)
♫  lord, I'm four  ♫
♫  lord, I'm 500 miles  ♫
♫  from my home  ♫
♫  500 miles  ♫
ladybug: Fellas...
We need to come up with a plan.
(pouring liquid)
You killed my brother.
You killed my brother,
you piece of shit!
I ought a...
Yeah, you, you,
you fucking shot me!
Hey.
I'll shoot you
in the fucking throat next time,
and your partner
Keira knightley! Hey.
I'll shoot the fuck out of her!
Hey! Hey! Fellas.
When we are so quick to anger,
we are slow to understand.
Yeah, well, I'm fast
to kick your ass, though,
I swear to god.
(overlapping shouting)
(grunting, yelling)
Lemon: Fucking piece of shit!
I should've put a bullet
through your ass!
When you point a finger
at someone in blame,
there are four fingers
pointing back at you.
Or th-three.
That's weird.
Fuck it!
That's it!
You know what I could do!
We before me!
Get off! Get the fuck off me!
Lemon: You before fucking god...
Gentlemen!
Get off me!
A plum does not resent
the hungry man
but the farmer
who planted the tree.
He resents the...
Resents the farmer?
So how do plum-plums have
fuckin' resentments now?
Ladybug: Oh...
So how can it resent?
Listen. The White Death
is the farmer.
So w-we're the plums.
We're the plums?
Lemon: It don't make sense.
Why are you motherfuckers
using metaphors?
Look, he shot
my fucking brother!
You shot my son!
We prepare together,
or we die alone.
That's all I was trying to say.
♫  ♫
The White Death waits for you
with his army of assassins.
Killers from all countries.
But he has no idea
my son and I are on this train.
If fate wills,
I will get my revenge.
Kimura: I'll head for the back
and stop as many as I can.
Lemon: I'll go to the driver car
and get us the fuck out of here.
What are you gonna do, joburg?
I'm gonna buy us some time.
♫  ♫
(gunshot echoes)
(song fades)
♫  ♫
Daughter.
Father.
♫  ♫
(rapid beeping)
Ladybug: Hey, uh, fellas,
I'm looking for a Mr. Death.
Got his case here.
Hey, easy.
(groans)
(coughs)
(sighs)
(blade rings)
Hurt people hurt people.
(in English)
I came to see you.
Hmm.
And to make you finally see me.
The real me.
Mm.
I built myself up
from the nothing you gave me.
All so I could be
the one in front of you today...
my finger on the trigger.
I was the one...
...who deserved your attention.
(spits)
Your love.
I'm more like you
than that little fuck up ever was.
(prince gasps)
(chuckling)
Do it.
I came here to kill you.
So kill me.
Kill me like you did all
the others who tried the same.
(laughs softly)
(breathes deeply)
Do it.
(beeping)
Fucking do it!
(yells sharply)
(gasps)
Pow.
(chuckles)
(in English)
I see you, dochka.
I always have.
But you have never been part of my plan.
(breathes shakily)
We found the American!
White Death: (in English)
What about the others?
They're all dead.
Uh, good news is
I have your case.
Ay, good news, good news.
White Death: (in English) Check the case.
(man) Hurry. (clicks tongue)
Move. Let's go.
Clear the train.
Lemon: All right, Thomas.
(laughs)
Time for you to start up...
Oh, shit,
everything's in Japanese.
There is no episode
in Japanese. What the f...
♫  ♫
(breathing heavily)
(man muffled) Get on the ground!
Man, I got a bad feeling
about this.
We have no idea
what's in this case.
Man, what are you talkin' about?
Uh, why is it always gotta be us
that opens this shit?
Just open the goddamn case.
I'd like to keep
my fuckin' arms.
Uh, Mr. Death, if I may?
The shadow buyer, um,
who bought all our contracts,
got us all on this-this train...
Uh, me, the hornet,
uh, tangerine, lemon...
Ho!
Oh!
That was you, right?
Yes, very astute.
I brought you on this train
hoping you'd kill each other.
Okay. Well, um...
If-if I could...
Why?
Why you do what you do?
You know, I've been asking
that very question.
If it's so safe,
why didn't he just open it?
What if it's a bomb
and it blows up in our faces?
You think these stupid masks
are gonna protect us?
♫  ♫
(laughs softly)
All these years later...
the burden of your betrayal
still heavy upon your heads.
Let me relieve you of both.
My wife...
Was taken from me.
(engine revving)
I heard.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
It was a horrible accident...
(laughing)
Horrible.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No.
Nothing in life is an accident.
It was an assassination
attempt on me.
But fate...
fate put two
wet work operatives,
twins, on a job in Bolivia...
Butchering my entire crew.
And I had to go deal with it.
And he didn't hire
two random operators, lemon.
No, he asked
for the two responsible
for the Bolivia job.
That is why
it was my wife
in the car that night,
not me.
Fate put my wife
in the hospital.
A piece of her rib
piercing her heart.
Only the most skilled
cardiovascular surgeon
could save her life.
But two nights earlier,
this surgeon was poisoned.
(screaming)
Oh, my god!
Fate.
Fate again.
(machine flat lining)
(straining) They said my
money was in the case.
Don't want to sound judgmental,
but if you hired the hornet,
you had your own kid killed?
Oh, yes.
Okay.
Oh, yes, I did.
The piece of shit.
Please, please.
White Death: That night, I told her...
I want you to please pick me up.
Not to leave.
To wait for me.
But she promised
it was the last time
we would ever
bail him out of trouble.
I will come.
I will always come for you.
Well, I suppose she was right.
If I had amputated that weakness
out of my life years ago,
she would still be by my side!
Yeah, it helps to process this.
I-I-I have a good therapist.
I loved my wife very much.
She taught me a valuable lesson.
If you do not control
your fate...
It will control you.
Mm. Mm?
So I took control.
I brought them all here to die.
♫  ♫
But now there is only one left.
Mr. Carver.
Wh...?
Uh... (stammers) Excuse me?
I'm filling in for carver?
Calling in sick?
Fuck carver.
The man who murdered my wife.
Bro.
Just open it!
Fine. You happy?
Ladybug: I'm not carver!
(screaming)
♫  ♫
(gurgling)
He went that way! Come...
(grunts)
(rapid gunfire)
(grunting)
(groaning weakly)
(quietly)
All right.
(train banging)
Oh, shit. Okay.
(automated recording
repeating in Japanese)
Oh, shit.
Something's happening.
(clunking)
Oh! Oh! (laughing)
{"Holding Out For A Hero" by
Miki Asakura plays in Japanese}
(man cries out)
(yelling)
(men shouting)
Excuse me.
(sighs)
Yep.
♫  Hero...  ♫
(song continues in Japanese)
(yelling, grunting)
(toy squeaking)
(yelling)
(squeaking)
(screams)
(yells)
(body thuds)
♫  Hero...  ♫
(song continues in Japanese)
(cries out)
(song stops abruptly)
(yells)
(body thuds)
(wind whistling)
Kimura.
Why are you here?
Your daughter.
It would seem she pushed...
the wrong grandson off a roof.
Ah, children.
You do the best you can
to raise them right.
Cockroach, I do not know
why you are here,
but move out of my way
or you will join your wife.
Our paths were destined
to return to each other.
(whooshing)
Okay. Right.
Fuckin' slow down, mate.
Come on!
Hey, so far so good.
You can stop the train.
Lemon: Uh, about that. I
took the velocity of the train
and divided it by the mass,
and I realized that I don't know
how to fuckin' drive
a bullet train!
Dude, all you do
is talk about trains.
Man, Thomas is
a metaphor for life,
not how to actually drive...
Get down!
♫  ♫
(yelling)
Shit.
♫  ♫
I got this! Stop the train!
What?!
(Lemon yelling)
Hiyah!
(Ladybug groans)
(grunting)
(metal clanging)
♫  ♫
(grunts)
♫  Stabbed with a star  ♫
♫  the hammer is on us
we'll live through the dark  ♫
♫  it's evel knievel  ♫
(crackling)
♫  It's got, it's got...  ♫
(song stops abruptly)
(yelling)
♫  ♫
(grunts)
(grunting)
(straining)
(grunts, chokes)
English, English, English.
English, English. Brakes!
We're good! I got it!
No!
(yells)
Hold on!
We're on the wrong track!
(shouting)
(both yelling)
♫  ♫
Lemon: Oi, joburg!
What?!
(grunts)
(growling)
I'm sorry I shot you!
Actually, it was, like, twice!
Oh.
Sorry?
You shot me twice!
(grunts)
(pained grunt)
Lemon: Oi!
(grunting)
I'm sorry I shot you twice.
Thanks, man!
That shows real growth!
(alarm beeping)
(squirting weakly)
Fuck! Fuck!
(cries out)
♫  ♫
You are not ruled by strength.
You are ruled by fear!
Fear of the one thing deep down
you cannot control!
(grunts)
Fear of fate!
Hey, and I'm sorry
about tangerine.
Yeah.
But I got another brother now.
Really?
Fuck no!
(Lemon growling)
(Lemon yelling)
♫  ♫
(flames whooshing)
For old times' sake.
(clicking)
(clicks)
Ah.
(crackles)
(clicks)
(song playing in Japanese)
(crackling)
♫  ♫
(clicks)
Fuck it.
(song stops)
(train thudding)
(brakes screeching)
{"Sukiyaki" by Kyu Sakamoto
playing in Japanese}
(coins jingling)
(clicking buttons)
♫  ♫
$♪%♪
Lemon: Oi.
That'll be 20.
Let's go.
Oh, mate.
Tangerine: Yeah?
I wanted bubble milk tea.
How about a wagon wheel?
Yeah.
(high-pitched squealing)
Ho!
Oh!
(fizzing)
(gunshot)
(song continues in Japanese)
(groans)
(grunts)
(gunshot)
(laughing)
(engine winding down)
A father...
protects his family.
(alarm beeping)
(Ladybug yelling)
(distorted animated music
playing)
(clunks)
(crackling)
(high-pitched squeaking)
(distorted animated music
playing)
(music stops)
(metallic creaking)
(crackling)
(Ladybug grunts)
(groans in pain)
(grunts, sighs heavily)
(spits)
Huh.
Uh...
(sighs)
♫  ♫
Oh, fuck.
About your wife,
I had nothing to do with that.
It's a mistake.
I'm not carver.
I only do snatch and grab jobs.
The carver, I want the carver!
I hired the carver!
Yeah, no, he had
a stomach thing, man.
I'm just filling in.
You're filling in.
For what it's worth,
carver is a dick.
The most cunning assassin,
maybe the laziest, but...
(gun clicking)
(clicking)
(groaning)
Aw, come on.
Just let it go, bro.
Do not call me "bro"!
Okay.
(grunts)
(gunshot echoing)
Ladybug: Ooh.
Oh.
(groans in disgust)
Dude, did you see that?
What was that?
Dude.
It's done.
Ladybug: Hey, about this plum.
Shouldn't the plum
give up all resentment?
Like...
(rapid gunfire)
Oh, my god.
(breathlessly)
It's my luck that delivered
my father's corpse at my feet.
The narcissism on this chick.
Untreatable.
Now I am...
Okay, wait, wait.
Wait.
What?
What is with
this fucked-up family?
You need some suggested
reading, if I may.
Surviving borderline
personality disorder.
What?
I highly recommend it.
Now I, I am the white d...
(tires screeching)
Ladybug: What was that?
Was that kar... was that Karma?
Farewell, ten to um us hi.
Tangerine.
(Kimura grunting)
(distant sirens wailing)
Whoa.
(distant sirens wailing,
emergency horns honking)
(siren wailing)
Maria?
Take the gun.
Oh, my god,
did you just say "whack"?
We're almost there.
You just need to get up.
Did you come to rescue me?
Did you need rescuing?
You came to rescue me.
Please don't make me regret it.
(mouthing)
Okay, don't. Don't.
What's happening to your face?
Are you, are you crying?
It's a lot to process.
I want you to know,
you are the greatest,
most wonderful handler
that I could ever have.
Ever. Ever.
Mm. Mm.
Do you think maybe there was
a little head trauma?
Maybe.
Little bit, yeah.
A little light-headed.
Yeah.
Need a banana?
Potassium might be good.
Have one in the car.
Hey, next time, take the gun.
Don't listen to Barry.
Okay? Simple?
(sniffling)
(quietly)
Stop it.
Shh. Stop.
You know, I think you were
right about one thing.
Usually am. Come on.
Maybe it is just about
how we frame it.
Like, maybe there's no bad luck
or good luck.
Maybe we're all just
agents of fate.
Ooh, nice car.
Yes, it is.
Try not to bleed on it.
(crackling)
(distant sirens wailing)
Holy mol...
Oh.
Well...
How do you know
it's a bad thing?
Huh?
Really?
See what I'm doing?
I do.
Turning that upside down.
This is working.
(car alarm chirps)
Yeah.
{"I Just Want To Celebrate"
by Rare Earth intro plays}
♫  One, two, three, four...  ♫
Ooh. Wasabi peas.
Fate obviously didn't want me
to have that banana.
Fate did not want us
to get in that car.
Maria: Well, maybe you've
learned something after all.
Ladybug: Fate needs
me to find a smart toilet.
Maria: I take that
back. Can you hold it?
Ladybug: I'm ball pointing.
Walk faster.
Ladybug: Okay. Yeah.
♫  That's why I'm telling you  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate
yeah, yeah  ♫
♫  another day of living, yeah  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate
another day of life  ♫
♫  had my hand
on the dollar bill  ♫
♫  and the dollar bill
flew away  ♫
♫  but the sun is shining
down on me  ♫
♫  and it's here to stay  ♫
(yells, gasping)
I'm alive! I'm Ali...
Oh, fuck me. Fuck me.
(panting)
(burbling, gasping)
Come on, you fucker.
Fuck you!
♫  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate  ♫
stop! Stop! Fucking stop!
Tangerines?
Fuck diesels.
Prince: I...
I am the white d...
Fuck you, diesel bitch!
(laughing)
Final curtain, huh?
Final curtain!
Take a fucking bow!
♫  Yeah, I just want
to celebrate  ♫
♫  another day of livin'  ♫
♫  yeah, I just want
to celebrate  ♫
♫  another day of life  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate  ♫
♫  said I just want
to celebrate  ♫
♫  celebrate  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate  ♫
♫  I want to celebrate  ♫
♫  I got to celebrate  ♫
♫  I just want to celebrate...  ♫
(song fades)
{"Kill Me Pretty"
by Tamio Okuda playing}
(gun racking rhythmically)
(Tamio Okuda vocalizing)
♫  Kill me, kill me
kill me pretty  ♫
♫  kill me, kill me
(song continues in Japanese)
♫  Kill me, kill me
kill me pretty  ♫
♫  kill me, kill me
(song continues in Japanese)
♫  ♫
(song fades out,
fades back in again)
♫  Yeah  ♫
♫  yeah  ♫
(song fades)
♫  ♫
(music ends)