I-Illumination!
Yeah! Illumination!
Whoo! Ha-ha-ha!
- Huh?
- Aw, man.
Aw.
Hmm. Whoa.
Past the place
that you come from,
far beyond what you've seen,
is a town like your town,
if your town was a dream.
Only it's not a dream
or a hoax or a ruse.
- Morning!
- It is Christmas in Who-ville,
- the home of the Whos.
- Hey!
Fresh peppermint bread!
- Oh, hey, Marge.
- Morning, Fred.
Smells like Christmas.
Whoa! Where are you going?
- Hey, Tom.
- Good to see you, Ted.
Wreath Man! Wreath Man!
Here you go, kid.
Have a wreath.
- Oh, cool!
- Merry Christmas to ya!
Have a great day, dear!
- You, too, hon! See you tonight!
- Hey!
Hurry up! Morning.
Yes, Who-ville is great,
that is known far and wide,
and three weeks
through December,
this place hits its stride.
Yes, the Whos
down in Who-ville
like Christmas a lot.
But the Grinch in his cave,
north of Who-ville...
did not.
Hmm?
Max...!
Ooh!
I am starving.
Huh?
Max.
What is this depressing bean?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's impossible.
We can't be out of food.
Wha...?
Where's my personal reserve
of moose juice?
And goose juice?
My emergency stash of Who Hash?
And my secret slew
of frozen Beezle-Nut stew?
I specifically bought enough
food to last until January.
How much emotional eating
have I been doing?
No. I won't. I will not.
I am not going to Who-ville
during Ch...
Chri...
Christmas! Ugh!
Ugh!
Fine. But I'm going to despise
every second of it.
Come on, Max.
Yes, the Grinch
hated Christmas,
the whole Christmas season.
Now, please don't ask why.
No one quite knows the reason.
It could be his head
wasn't screwed on just right.
It could be perhaps that
his shoes were too tight.
But I think the most likely
reason of all
may have been that his heart
was two sizes too small.
Now, remember, Max,
this is the time of year
when the Whos
are at their most deceptive.
You have my full permission
to attack anyone who so much
as says one kind word to us.
Okay, let's go.
- Morning, fellas.
- Greetings.
- Ready for Christmas?
Ah, good to see you.
How's work?
Oh, could be better,
could be worse.
Oh, hi. Merry Christmas.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait! Hold the bus!
- Wait. Stop. Oh, sor...
- Whoa!
- Coming through.
- Hey!
Wait! Wait! Sam! Hold the bus!
Oh!
Whoa!
- Whew! Oh!
- Sorry, Donna.
That's okay, Sam.
Thanks for stopping.
- Whew!
- They still got you on the night shift, huh?
- Sure do.
- Oh, by the way,
Cindy-Lou forgot
her hockey... stick.
Hmm.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh. Thanks, mister.
Ah-ha.
Hey!
- Hmm.
- Huh?
You're a mean one, mister.
It's really such an awful day.
- Hey! Merry Christmas!
- Huh?
Happy holidays, Sue.
Good morning, Fred.
Season's greetings, folks.
And Merry Christmas to you...
Ugh.
Huh?
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah...!
Oh, hello.
Happy holi...
Uh-uh.
Blech!
Ah. What's this?
Excuse me.
Are you getting that?
I need it
for my Christmas stuffing.
Mmm... no.
Well, that's not very nice.
Oh, sugarplum!
Oh, no, I can't today.
I have a list of errands
a mile long, and the babysitter
left the sink backed up.
No, I-I'm not complaining.
I'm venting.
There's a difference.
Okay. Uh, talk to you later.
I-I have to get breakfast
on the table.
Right after I unclog
this drain again.
Ugh! It's like concrete!
- Cindy-Lou, sweetheart, come eat.
- Coming!
Oh.
Buster,
we've talked about this.
- Huh?
- Your brother's head is not breakfast.
Uh?
Blah!
Ah!
Okay.
You all right, Mom?
Me? Oh. Yes. Never better.
Ah. What'd you put down here
anyway, a roller skate?
No. Just batter.
Me and Ms. Wilbur made cookies.
Oh. That explains it.
- Come have some eggs.
- I can't.
I gotta go mail something.
But I made the beds
and put away the twins' toys.
Thanks, sweetheart.
You didn't have to do that.
I don't mind.
- Something's burning.
- Just a second, sweetie.
Bean, don't feed your brother
with your feet.
- Mom! The toast!
- I got it!
Wait. Where are you
going again?
- I told you. To mail a letter.
- Okay,
but just come here first.
Mom. I gotta go.
All right.
Mwa!
Okay. Now you can go.
Thanks, Mom.
Bye, Buster. Bye, Bean.
Don't do anything
I wouldn't do.
Roger that, Mom.
Whoo!
Here goes Cindy-Lou Who
as she dashes through the snow
with a very important letter!
Oh, no!
I'm gonna miss the mailman!
Shortcut!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Whoo! Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Bon appétit!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, no!
Whoo!
Aah...
Watch out!
Aah! Oh!
No! My letter!
What is wrong with you?
Didn't you see me?
I mean, if that...
if that was a sled, I-I...
well, I'd be dead.
I'm sorry for bumping into you,
but this is really important.
Have you seen my letter?
And that right there, Max,
is the true nature
of the Who child:
just right to "me, me, me.
- My letter. Me, me, me."
- No, you don't understand.
This isn't just a letter.
This is the letter.
Oh... really?
Let me guess.
Small child, December 20,
rabidly searching for a
"really important" lost letter?
Might it be your list
of demands to Santa?
They're not demands.
It's more like a wish.
And what I'm wishing for
is really, really important.
Well, then why send a letter?
I mean, if it's really
that important, you should
just ask him face-to-face.
Oh, but that's right:
no one's ever seen him.
Mmm, my bad.
Come on, Max,
let's get out of here.
Bye, doggy.
There he is, Max.
The happiest Who alive.
The unbearable...
Bricklebaum.
He thinks we're friends.
Quick. Let's make a run for it.
Go, go!
Wha...? Wh-What was that?
No.
Oh, my goodness,
Mr. Grinch! I-I-I'm coming!
Leave Mr. Grinch alone.
That's one tough balloon
that you're fighting there.
You old feisty frosty.
Here, come on,
let me help you up.
I-I-I do not want or need
your help.
Oh. "Hair dye.
Gorgeous Green Goddess."
Oh. How did that get in there?
Hey, I'm sorry
if I made you uncomfy.
We all got to keep
the gray away.
I myself use
Chocolate Explosion.
You know what? If you want
to apologize for something,
apologize for that.
My eyes are burning.
Well, don't-don't blame me.
Haven't you heard?
The mayor wants Christmas to be
three times bigger this year.
That means
three times the lights,
three times the eggnog,
three times the...
Information needed.
That's a good one.
Oh, I get it.
This is one of
your kidding things.
Finally, something
you said is...
actually funny.
Yeah, I do kid a lot,
but no, this is actually...
- Christmas three times bigger!
- Well, you're just gonna have
- a good time with this, aren't you?
- Oh-ho, dear.
- Oh, no, no, no, I-I-I-I...
- I gotta say, it's really nice
- to see you laughing.
- Sorry, I-I can't hear you.
I don't speak ridiculous.
Oh, you're a scream.
- Have a nice life. Good-bye.
- I'll see you later.
Whew! Oh, man.
Mr. Grinch.
I'm gonna stay awake
to see Santa!
From the edge of his ledge,
way up in the sky,
the Grinch felt upset,
though he wasn't sure why.
It could've been Christmas,
all that joy and the such,
or some thoughts from his past
that he just
couldn't quite touch.
But whatever it was,
it made his heart moan.
Though he was used to it now,
this being alone.
And now safe in his cave,
and apart from the fray,
he reminded himself...
It is better this way.
That's right, yeah.
Just right there.
No. No, not on your brother.
Let Mommy do it.
Whoa! Whoa...
Cindy-Lou!
Don't worry, Mom.
Aah.
I'm wearing four ski jackets.
Four jackets?
Aren't you a little hot?
Yep. Sweatin' a little bit.
Are you going somewhere?
- North Pole.
- Oh. Wow.
Any, uh, particular reason?
- I got to talk to Santa.
- Santa, huh?
Yeah. It's really important.
Well, it must be if you need
to go see him in person.
- It sure is.
- Okay, then. Well, good luck,
and I guess I'll see you
in about a month.
Wait. It takes a whole month
to get to the North Pole?
Oh, yeah. At least.
Christmas will be over
by the time I got there.
Ah, that's true. Now, we
would miss you at Christmas.
Wow. I guess I'm gonna have
to come up with another plan.
Hey, maybe while
you're thinking,
you could put the halo
on the angel.
Okay.
You want to take
your jackets off?
Yeah, at least
one or two of them.
No, boys, don't pull
the angel's wings off.
She needs those.
So, uh...
what do you want to do today?
No idea, huh?
Ooh. I got one.
All right, all right,
I'm sorry.
You're a good dog.
But a bad drummer.
What would you like to do?
More than embarrassing
to be beaten by a dog.
Oh. What's that?
And checkmate. Again.
What in the world is happening?
What is that?!
It's the most
beautiful Christmas tree
you've ever seen!
Three times bigger?
Th-Th-That's
a hundred times bigger!
Oh, you just wait
till we light it tonight.
It'll sparkle so bright,
you'll be celebrating Christmas
with the rest of us! Ho-ho!
Oh, man, I can't wait!
I'm gonna keep at it.
- I'll see you later, Grinchy.
- No.
You will not see me later!
And I will not be celebrating!
And that tree...
that... tree...
has got to go.
- Come on, Mom!
- Cindy-Lou, look over there.
- Wow! That's amazing!
- Thank you.
Ooh, a three-eyed sock monster!
Awesome robot.
MAYOR McGERKLE: Oh, how
marvelous this time of year is.
Welcome, Who-ville, to the
annual tree-lighting ceremony.
How spectacular
are these ornaments?
Look what I made, everybody.
It's a Christmas dragon.
It came to me in a dream.
Oh, man.
- Hey, Bartholomew.
- Hey there, Ms. Who.
- Here you go.
- Got it.
Find a good spot for it.
There it goes.
McGERKLE: Now, let's get ready
to flip that switch
and light up the sky!
Oh-ho, no.
Not on my watch, you don't.
See you guys soon.
Gonna go find Groopert.
Okay. Have fun. Bye. Say "bye."
Here you go. I hope your big
brother gets what he deserves.
Hey, Groopert.
How's business?
Good. What I can't sell...
I can always eat.
I need to talk to you about
something really important.
- Okay.
- Come on, let's go.
All right,
check this out, Groopert.
I'm gonna stay up
on Christmas Eve this year
and meet Santa Claus.
Whoa, that is crazy!
Yeah, I really got
to talk to him.
About what?
Well, it's really personal.
But I'm going to tell you,
because you're my best friend.
It's about my mom.
She works all night
and takes care of us all day.
And it just isn't fair.
She acts like she's fine...
but I know,
it's really hard for her.
So I figured, if anyone
could fix that, it'd be Santa.
Wow. And I just asked him
for a turtle.
McGERKLE: Here we go!
- Oh. It's starting!
- Okay, Who-ville, it is time
to light this beautiful tree.
...17, 18, 19 and 20.
Okay. Lock and load.
All right,
just attach this here,
and we'll be ready to launch.
I know.
I wish I could see
the look on their faces...
Whoa!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy! Hold on, hold on! Aah!
Whew! Oh, boy.
Whoa... okay, oh, boy.
That could've been
so much worse.
Aah...!
Let's begin the countdown.
Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven!
Six!
Five! Four!
- Three! Two!
- Hey!
My dragon can fly!
- One!
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
Oh, my.
No, no, no, no. No!
No! No! Aah!
- Whoa!
- Wow!
Oh, it's beautiful.
McGERKLE:
There it is.
The most beautiful tree
Who-ville has ever seen.
Oh, oh! No! No!
McGERKLE: Everyone,
have a wonderful season.
No.
He walked through the crowd,
and the sound and the lights...
...and his ears heard the thump
of their joy and delights.
And it took him right back
to his earliest years,
to that lost, lonely boy
who cried all of those tears.
That lost, lonely boy,
isolated and sad,
with no home of his own,
no mom and no dad.
And as the Grinch
looked around,
he felt downright scared...
...as he remembered
that Christmas
where nobody cared.
Where nobody showed,
not even a flea.
And there were no cards,
no gifts and no tree.
And as he watched other kids...
- Woop!
- ...one thing became clear:
that this was the single
worst day of the year.
And now here it was,
that day once again,
and he felt all those feelings
he felt way back when,
when he'd watch
Whos young and old
all sit down to feast,
and they'd feast,
feast, feast, feast.
They'd feast on Who-pudding
and rare Who roast beast.
Which is something the Grinch
could not stand in the least.
And then they'd do something
he liked least of all.
Every Who down in Who-ville,
the tall and the small,
would stand close together
with Christmas bells ringing.
They'd stand hand in hand,
and the Whos
would start singing.
They'll sing, and they'll sing,
and they'll sing,
sing, sing, sing!
Yes, he couldn't recall
without feeling the sting.
So the Grinch
finally declared...
I must stop this whole thing.
Why?
For 53 years,
I've put up with it.
Now...
I must stop this Christmas
from coming.
But how?
Then he got an idea.
An awful idea.
The Grinch got
a wonderful, awful idea.
I know just what to do.
I'm going to steal
their Christmas.
All the trimmings,
all the trappings,
all their gifts and garlands!
When they wake
and see it's gone,
then all their joy and
happiness will be gone as well.
So prepare yourself, Max.
For tomorrow...
We begin!
Genius starts
with the abs, Max.
It's go time.
And now...
the question we
have all been waiting for:
How will I steal Christmas?
Well, prepare to have
your little doggy mind blown.
Poof.
Ta-da!
That's right,
I become...
Santa Claus.
But instead of giving
all the joy and happiness,
I'll take it away.
If he can deliver Christmas to
the whole world in one night,
then I can certainly steal it
from little old Who-ville.
I mean, come on.
What's Santa have that I don't?
That's hurtful.
Um, what are you doing
with my bowling ball?
Chasing it.
And you're taking it where?
- It's a secret.
- All right.
But not without
breakfast. Catch!
Whoa! Waffles! My favorite!
Thanks! See you guys later!
Here we go.
- Hey, Cindy-Lou.
- Oh, hey there, Mr. Cubbins.
Ca-caw! Ca-caw!
Woot, woot.
- Ready.
- All right. Let's go.
Whoa!
Hold on!
Whoo!
Yeah!
Let's go, let's go.
Let's move.
Hang on.
- Whoo!
- And... dismount.
So, what do we know?
Waffles are delicious.
Super delicious. But I meant
about meeting Santa.
We know no one's ever done it.
Hmm...
Okay. How about this?
I'm going to sit
in the living room
with my eyes wide open
like this,
and if I start to drift off,
I'll just open them wider!
Um, I'm pretty sure
you're gonna fall asleep.
- And by the time you wake up...
- He'll be gone.
Nothing but cookie crumbs.
Yeah, you're right.
- I got it!
- Tell me!
Maple syrup.
All right, maple syrup.
We pour it on the roof,
the reindeer get stuck,
and then they can't fly away.
Science!
Won't the syrup just freeze?
- Good point.
- Also, how do we get
all that syrup on the roof?
Yeah, I got nothing.
Wait a minute.
- I think I got it.
- What?
We're gonna need
the whole gang for this one.
Okay.
If I'm going to become Santa,
then I need to get
into character.
All right, let's see.
"Christmas Tree."
"Christmas Traditions."
"Christmas Pudding."
How does pudding work its way
into everything?
Where is the Santa stuff?
Look at this.
Little girls and boys giggling
over sugarplums.
Oh.
Look how they did the roof
of the gingerbread house
with vanilla icing.
Little... family of gumdrops.
So dumb.
So, so stupidly dumb.
Ah, here we are.
"The Legend of Santa Claus."
Red suit, white beard,
always in a jolly mood.
Oh. That's not gonna happen.
Oh, well.
Let's just start
by finding ourselves
some reindeer.
Beautiful.
Isn't it, Max?
This, my little friend,
is the Rein-Horn.
It perfectly re-creates the
mating call of the reindeer.
Behold.
Oh. Hey there.
Sorry, little goat.
I was calling for a rein...
What was that?!
Scram! Skedaddle!
Strange goat.
Now, reindeer migrate,
so maybe we'll catch a few
headed south for the winter.
I also read that they tend
to mate in densely wooded...
Will you stop following us?!
Shoo! Away! Go back to the goat farm.
Go eat a can.
All right, now that that's
over, back to the task at hand.
Whew! It's a little crisp.
Oh, it's getting...
really... c-cold.
Oh, goodness!
Can't...
feel my lips.
Can't... blink.
Eyes... frozen!
Max...
we've hit the mother lode.
We'll have 100 reindeer
to pull our...
Huh?
Well, Santa had eight.
He looks like he ate
the other seven.
Watch and learn, Max.
All right.
Aah!
Uh-oh.
Aah! Frozen, stinkin'...
Stop. Stop.
Onward, my furry friends.
We're walking toward destiny.
- Let's get in there!
- Whoo-hoo!
All right, you called, we came.
- So what's up?
- Yeah, what's the deal?
Thanks for getting here
so fast, guys.
Follow me.
So, what's the big secret?
Yeah, I don't have very long.
My parents set the timer.
- Dude.
- Don't ask. It's new.
All right, everybody,
brace yourselves.
In exactly 48 hours,
we are going to do something
that's never been done before.
We're gonna...
trap Santa Claus!
Trap Santa?
Why would we want to do that?
Duh. To steal all his toys.
I love it.
- Oh, yeah!
- That's a great idea!
No, not to steal his toys.
To, um, to talk to him.
- What? Why do you want to talk to him?
- It's personal.
- Yeah, it's kind of personal.
- Well, I don't want
to do it if you
won't tell me why.
- What are you talking about, "personal"?
- Axl,
when you asked to borrow $16
and my mom's suitcase,
did I ask you why?
- No.
- And what about you, Ozzy?
Remember when you
got stuck in that...
All right, all right, okay.
Geez.
I did it
because you're my friend,
and when something
matters to you,
that means it matters to me.
- That's beautiful.
- Okay, okay, okay.
You convinced me.
- Count me in, too.
- All right, we're in.
- Great! Now, let's do this.
- Yeah, let's do this!
- Oh, yeah! Awesome!
- Let's make it happen.
Whoa, cool.
That is so cool.
- To the bikes!
- Yeah!
- Cindy-Lou! Dinnertime!
- Let's go, guys! Dinnertime!
- Time to eat!
- Ooh, dinner.
All right, we meet
first thing in the morning.
- Okay.
- All right, see you tomorrow.
- See you guys in the morning.
- Ozzy! Timer!
Okay, Mom.
This is the loudest snow
I've ever heard in my life.
You two, go around the back.
Wait for me to drop
the sleigh from the roof. Okay?
Go, team.
Ah-ah-ah-ah.
Shh.
Aah!
Whew!
Aah...!
What? Wha-What's going on?
Hey. Who taught Mabel
how to use the doorbell?
Man, that's awesome.
You smart little dog.
Huh? What's this?
All right, here it comes.
Get ready.
Aah!
You tell...
What? Oh!
Oh, look at that.
Mabel is delivering cakes now.
I mean, is this
the best Christmas, or what?
Oh... whoa!
Whoa...!
Oh! Holy moly!
Man, I don't know
what's in this cake,
but I think I just saw
Santa Claus.
Let me get another piece.
Today was great.
We did mean things,
and we did them in style.
Max, you know the rules.
You sleep in your bed,
and I sleep in...
Oh, no, no, not you, too.
I don't believe this.
Max, did you teach him
puppy eyes?
Fine.
This one time.
Ah...
Ah.
Mmm! Now, that is
a great cup of coffee.
Max, this morning, you and I
need to do some recon.
Fred, you just sit right there.
And don't touch anything.
Intel, Max,
that's what we're after.
How many houses are
in Who-ville,
and how many Whos?
How many wreaths and trees
and chimney flues?
I'll be in your ear
the whole time,
and whatever you're seeing,
I'll be seeing on the monitor.
Ready? Now, off you go, Max.
Fly, boy.
Fly!
Max, stop socializing.
Now, let's go in for a look.
Okay, six houses on Oak Street.
Oh, watch out!
Wha...?
- Huh.
- Okay, go. Go, go, go.
Now, cut through Main Street
and survey the south side.
Merry Christmas!
Look at those
greedy little gift monsters,
loading themselves up
with Christmas junk.
- Okay, Max, turn right here.
- Whoa!
So I woke up this morning,
got dressed, had my coffee,
went outside,
looked on the roof.
My sleigh was gone.
My, my, I wonder who took it.
Okay, let's see here.
If we do...
28 houses an hour
for six hours,
that would be sausages.
Sausages?!
Max! Don't even think about it.
Max!
Max, are you okay?
Max?
Oh, hey, look, it's me.
Oh, dear. Aah!
Bad dog.
Fred, we're home!
Fred...?
What are you... doing?
Okay.
Come on, we got work to do.
Now, let's plan our route.
First, now, we go south,
quick jaunt to the east,
and then this house, skip
the subdivision for the moment,
knock off the entire
southeast quadrant of the town,
and then we finish it all up...
on Whistling Who Lane.
That's 223 houses
and only seven hours
of darkness to work with.
That means we have to be
fast and focused.
And believe you me,
there will be temptation...
all around us.
Behold! The present.
This is our enemy.
You will want to unwrap it.
And... play with it.
But you must not!
And if you can get past
the present,
the only obstacle left is...
...the cookie.
Look at it in all
its red, sugary splendor.
No, no, no.
Look at yourselves.
Discipline. We must...
...resist.
- Are you ready?
- Almost.
Good. Think jolly.
- And fat.
- Okay, I'm ready.
All right, quick.
Everybody, hide.
Three, two, one,
cue Santa!
That means you, Groopert.
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
Look at this pretty house.
I will leave presents
for the people.
Come on, it's not
the school play, dude.
- Then why do I have to wear the outfit?
- Groopert!
Focus. Just get the cookie!
But I can see the strings.
Stop worrying.
It'll be dark at night.
What if he has a flashlight?
Have you ever seen a picture
of Santa with a flashlight?
- No, but I just...
- Groopert,
just pick up the cookie!
Hmm. What do we have here?
A delicious little cookie.
Aah!
Groopert!
Groopert?
Uh, hey, guys.
Do I still get to eat
the cookie?
All right, so I tinkered
with our sleigh a bit.
Behold!
Look at this, Max.
Now you'll be riding in style.
A throne for a barking prince.
How do you like that?
All right, Fred,
you are the engine
of this great machine.
Understood?
Good.
Now, remember,
this is just a practice run,
but on this team
we practice like we play.
So let's leave it all
out on the snow.
Oh! Okay!
All right, how about that?
Now, let's pick up the pace
and see how she handles.
Oh, ho-ho!
Hang on!
No, no, no. No problem.
It's all... under control.
Whoa!
Aah!
We're doing it, Max.
We are doing it!
We will not be...
...stopped?
What happened? Fred?
Oh, um...
sorry, but we don't need
any more reindeer.
No. Go. Get. Shoo.
I have what I need.
It's okay, Fred.
On our own again, Max.
It was the day
before Christmas,
and the Whos were abuzz,
all doing the things
that a Christmas Who does.
Some were out buying presents,
others just milled about.
- There you go, sir.
- But the whole town felt joyous,
of that there was no doubt.
The weather was perfect,
and soon snow would fall.
- This surely would be...
- All right, everyone ready?
...the best Christmas of all.
Max! There you are.
Check this out.
Whoa! Ah.
I've been making
lots of cool... Whoa!
...stuff!
Ooh, more coffee.
It's gonna be a big night.
We got all the gizmos
and gazmos we need,
but we still don't have
the proper outfit.
Come on, let's do
a little stitching.
There's only one thing
left to do.
Max?
Do you know what you are?
You are a sturdy little fella.
And loyal.
Very loyal.
In fact, I think
you're the best dog
a Grinch could hope for.
And that is why...
I'm promoting you.
Max...
you will guide
my sleigh tonight.
Ha-ha!
I knew you
wouldn't let me down.
It was now Christmas Eve.
There was joy in the air.
For in just a few hours,
Santa Claus would be there.
And the gifts would be left,
and the stockings all filled.
And the anticipation,
well, it started to build.
Ozzy, what are you doing?
Trying... to get...
myself tired.
All right, eight hours
till Christmas morning.
That's 28,800 seconds.
Okay, and... sleep!
Waffle One, this is Waffle Two.
Are you there? Over.
I read
you loud and clear, Waffle Two.
- This is Groopert, by the way.
- Yeah, I got that.
Oh. I just wanted
to wish you good luck
- with Santa Claus.
- Thanks. Talk tomorrow.
So, you got any
last-minute wishes for Santa?
Yep. I have one great big wish.
Good. Because you deserve
everything you want and more.
Thanks, Mom.
I want the same thing for you.
How did I end up
with such a wonderful daughter?
I don't know.
Sometimes you just get lucky.
Well, then I really did.
Me, too.
I love you, Mom.
I love you, sweetheart.
- Good night.
The Grinch was now
ready to start his big trip.
He stood like a captain
aboard a great ship.
Yes, the time had now come
to take off like a shot.
Here we go, Max.
Let's see what you've got!
Hyah!
What?
Max?
Max, are you okay?
Huh?
Yeah, Max!
Attaboy!
Go, boy! Go!
And down the Grinch came
on his great fateful ride,
toward the good homes
of Who-ville
and the Christmas inside.
He had planned it
and prepped it,
big detail to small.
Yes, he'd get rid
of Christmas now,
once and for all.
You take the outside,
I'll take the inside.
House number one.
He was ready to pounce
and set the score right.
He'd make up for the past,
and he'd do it tonight.
Okay...
now, let's steal Christmas.
He swept up their presents
with the speed of a wiz.
And he knew he'd cause sadness.
Only theirs now, not his.
All this excess and nonsense,
it was all about greed.
About meaningless stuff
that they didn't even need.
Yeah.
The Grinch went to work.
He scooped up the toys.
He raced against time.
He raced against joy.
He hit a few snags
as he made his way through.
An angry orange cat...
and a sleepwalking Who.
Huh?
Thank you, Mommy.
He stole pop guns and bicycles,
roller skates, drums,
checker boards, tricycles,
popcorn and plums.
Gadgets and gizmos,
and dolls with strange names,
goofballs and shloof-balls
and video games.
And he swiped and he poached.
Yes, the stealing was on.
And this day that he hated,
well, he made it be gone.
This is it, the last house.
Ha!
Huh?
Oh, what the heck?
Ah.
Huh?
He's here!
Whoa. What the...?
Aah! Whoa. Whoa! Aah!
How do I get out of this?
Santa Claus.
Oh. Uh, hello.
A little help, please?
I'll let you down.
Just give me a minute.
Oh, that would be great.
I'm coming.
Just trying to remember...
which cord it is.
Oh, no!
I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I-I guess so.
Let me help you.
Sit down here.
- Whew.
- Drink this.
It'll make you feel better.
Uh... thanks.
Wow. I can't believe
it's really you.
Uh... yeah.
I'm so sorry about the trap
and everything,
but I really need...
Hey. Why are you taking
our Christmas tree?
Well...
uh, one of the lights
wasn't working,
so I thought I'd
take it back to the workshop
and see if I could fix it.
I didn't know you did that.
Yeah. Sure.
Now, why don't you
go back upstairs to bed,
and then when you wake up,
the tree will be fixed
- and your presents will be waiting under it.
- Wait.
You don't understand.
I don't want presents.
Of course you do.
Everyone wants presents.
No, no, really, I don't.
I want you to help my mom.
Y-Your mom?
Yeah. She works so hard
and is always doing stuff
for other people.
And I just want her
to be happy.
You want me to help...
your mom?
You're Santa.
You make people happy.
And everyone
should be happy, right?
Y-Yeah, I...
I guess they should.
Santa,
are... are you okay?
What?
Uh... yeah. I'm fine.
Now, why don't you go
back up to bed, hmm?
Okay.
I wish you could celebrate
with us tomorrow.
We all get together and sing.
It's so beautiful that
if you close your eyes
and listen,
all of your sadness
just goes away.
That sounds nice.
Huh?
Thank you, Santa.
Good night.
Good-good night.
I just met
the strangest little Who girl.
All right, Max. Let's go.
He tried to forget it,
but the words filled his head,
and he found himself thinking
about what the young girl
had said.
It was hard to imagine.
Could it really be true?
But if they could all be happy,
maybe he could be, too.
What?
Her head felt unsteady,
and her heart was just sick.
- Oh, no.
- It must be a joke
or a prank or a trick.
Who would do such a thing?
Who would stoop down this low?
And then one little girl
realized...
she might just know.
3,000 feet up,
up the side of Mount Crumpit,
the Grinch rode with his load
to the tip-top to dump it.
Keep going.
We're gonna make it.
Oh, dear.
Wha... What happened?
- Where's the decorations?
- All the presents. - Aw, man.
Mom... it's my fault.
What... What is?
All of this.
I-I trapped Santa last night,
'cause I wanted to ask him to
do something special for you.
But I think I made him mad,
and that's why he stole
everyone's Christmas.
No. No, no. No, honey,
this isn't your fault.
He didn't steal Christmas.
He just stole stuff.
Christmas is in here.
And besides, I already have the
greatest gift I could ever get.
You.
Just one more shove.
What's that? Do you hear it?
They're singing?
I don't understand, Max.
Don't they know what I've done?
As he watched the small girl,
he thought he might melt.
If he did what she did,
would he feel what she felt?
And the luscious sound swelled,
reaching up to the skies.
And the Grinch heard
with his heart,
and it tripled in size.
What? Oh, no.
Oh! Aah!
No, no, no, no!
Oh, no!
Aah...!
No, don't worry.
I got it.
Max, it's okay. I'm...
Aah!
Whoa, oh...
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Max...!
Oh!
Fred?
You...
you came back.
Max, the gifts.
We have to return them.
And having heard
the Whos' goodness,
having felt the Whos' song,
he tried to make right
what he had made wrong.
Uh...
hello, everybody.
it was me.
I stole your Christmas.
I stole it because...
because I thought
it would fix something
that happened a long time ago.
But it didn't.
And I'm sorry.
I'm so very sorry.
For everything.
Not now, Max.
I need to be alone.
I-I-I kind of thought
you might like it.
You don't like it?
Oh, I could take it back.
It's not a big deal.
I just thought maybe you...
Oh. Hey.
Merry Christmas
to you, too, Max.
Ha!
Uh, that's gonna get old.
What was that?
Huh?
Uh... hello.
Hi.
Remember me?
Yes. Yes, I do.
I remember you.
My name is Cindy-Lou.
Cindy-Lou Who.
It's nice to meet you,
Cindy-Lou.
Uh, oh, m-my name is Grinch.
And, uh, th-this is Max.
Whoa! Nice to meet you, Max.
I just came to invite you to
our house for Christmas dinner.
What? Me?
But I took your gifts.
- Yeah, I know.
- And your trees.
Yup.
I stole your whole Christmas.
I know you did.
But we're inviting you anyway.
But why?
Because... you've been alone
long enough.
Dinner's at 6:00.
Don't be late.
And make sure you bring
your sweet doggy, too.
Right. Okay.
Hmm.
Um, this is a bad idea.
I-I-I can't...
I can't do this,
I can't do this.
They're all gonna hate me.
All right.
Mm!
I did it.
Oh! Mr. Grinch!
I'm so happy
you decided to come.
Welcome.
Th-Thank you for inviting me.
Uh, I-I wore a tie.
And it's a very nice tie.
Cindy-Lou! Look who came!
Mr. Grinch! You're here!
Hello.
Come on in.
I'll show you around.
Oh. Okay.
Hello, Mr. Grinch.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Aunt Ida,
I'd like you to meet
my friend, the Grinch.
Oh, it's nice to meet you,
Mr. Grinch.
Thank you.
It's nice to be here.
Oh, here,
let me take that for you.
Oh. Thank you.
Cindy-Lou, could you make a
little room for this, please...
No, don't worry.
I-I've got it.
Huh. Isn't that thoughtful?
- Well, is that grouchy, grumpy...
- Huh?
- ...Grinchy I see standing over there? Ha-ha!
- Bricklebaum.
- Good to see you.
- Come on, Grinchy,
- give me a hug!
- Oh!
It don't count if you
don't hug back, buddy.
Okay, come take your seats,
everyone. Dinner's ready.
Come on.
You're sitting next to me.
Here you go.
Oh. Oh.
This is
my first Christmas dinner.
- What happens?
- You'll see.
Would you... do the honors,
Mr. Grinch?
Oh. Uh, okay.
Do you mind
if I say something first?
Not at all.
Um, well, everybody,
I-I just want to say...
I've spent my entire life
hating Christmas
and everything about it.
But now I see that it
wasn't Christmas I hated.
It was being alone.
But I'm not alone anymore.
And I have all of you
to thank for it.
But especially...
this little girl right here.
Ma'am, your daughter's kindness
changed my life.
That's my girl.
Oh...
that was beautiful.
That's my best friend.
Merry Christmas, Mr. Grinch.
Merry Christmas, Cindy-Lou.
And the Grinch raised his glass
and led the Whos in a toast.
To kindness and love,
the things we need most.