(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(DIGITAL TRILLING)
(WHOOSHING)
(BEEPING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(CRACKS NECK)
(BEEPING)
(BUTTON BEEPS)
BUZZ: Buzz Lightyear
mission log, stardate 3901.
Sensors have detected potential life forms
on an uncharted planet.
So, we're making a detour to investigate.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Space rangers
will make initial evaluation,
then assess whether it's worth
waking the science crew
from their hyper sleep.
While the ERIC takes core samples,
I will explore further the oddities
of this strange planet.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
(LOUD BREATHING THROUGH HELMET)
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
No readout yet if the air is breathable.
There seems to be no sign
of intelligent life anywhere.
-Who are you talking to?
-Uh, no one.
You were narrating again.
I was not. Just doing the mission log.
You do know no one ever listens to those.
I know that. Narrating helps me focus.
-Stay sharp.
-Yeah.
Well, if it bothers you,
Commander Hawthorne,
I'm happy to wait back on the turnip.
Please don't call it the turnip.
But the ship looks like a root vegetable.
Yes. You made that very clear
at the design review.
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYS)
How long have you known that I narrate?
Forever. Since you and I were cadets.
Speaking of, you forgot
to take the rookie with you.
Ugh, Commander Hawthorne,
you know how I feel about rookies.
The same way I feel about autopilots.
(MOCKINGLY) "How may I assist you?
"Is there anything I can do, sir?"
They don't help. They just
overcomplicate things.
I'm better off just doing the job myself.
Which is why I brought the rookie.
(DRAMATIC MUSICAL FLOURISH)
Uh, hello.
No.
Buzz, protocol requires
we bring him along.
-He's gonna have sad eyes.
-ALISHA: Buzz.
You know I can't deal with sad eyes.
ALISHA: Look at the rookie, Buzz.
-Nope.
-Look at the... Look...
-No... No. No.
-ALISHA: Lightyear.
-Look at him.
-Not looking.
-ALISHA: Look.
-No.
-Look, look, look.
-No, no, no.
-Look at the rookie.
-(SIGHS HEAVILY)
(SOFT MUSICAL FLOURISH)
All right. All right! You win.
(BUZZ SIGHS)
Look, Feather... Featherings... Feather...
It's Featheringhamstan, sir.
Look, rookie. First, you will
not speak unless spoken to.
-Yes, sir.
-Still talking.
Second, respect the suit.
This suit means something.
It's not just protecting your body.
-It's protecting the universe.
-(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
This suit is a promise to the world
that you and you alone
will do one thing above all.
Finish the mission, no matter the cost.
-(MUSIC CRESCENDOING)
-You will never quit,
whatever the galaxy may throw your way.
Will you please turn that off!
-(CLICK, MUSIC STOPS)
-(ALISHA LAUGHS)
It's just too easy.
You're mocking me, aren't you?
Yeah, but in a supportive way.
Look, what I'm trying to say, Commander,
is that you and I have this job down.
-Uh, sir.
-Still talking.
At any moment I know what you're thinking,
-I know where you're gonna be.
-(GRUNTING)
-(YELLS)
-But this guy, I don't know.
Where'd he go?
Ugh! You see,
this is exactly what I'm talking about.
He's not helping. He's wandered off.
ALISHA: Vines!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BUZZ GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
-Bugs!
-(EXCLAIMS)
(BUGS SCREECH)
The ship. It's sinking.
Everyone, back to the turnip!
Oh, so now it's the turnip.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Engage stealth mode.
It should buy us enough time.
(BEEPING)
BUZZ: We're not gonna make it.
ALISHA: Almost there!
-Okay, plan B. Ready?
-Go!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
-Blast!
-Here. I can reroute it.
Just gimme a minute.
Where is the...
FEATHERINGHAMSTAN: Help!
(SOFT MUSICAL FLOURISH)
(SIGHS) Rookie.
Help me! (SCREAMS)
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
Planet clearly uninhabitable.
-In fact, outright hostile.
-Whoa! (SCREAMS)
Sentient foliage have apprehended
Cadet Furth-Feathering...
Featheringston... Feather...
Oh, they got the rookie,
who I strongly suggested
should not have joined
in the first... (GRUNTS)
-(WHIMPERING)
-Blast.
-(WEAPON FIRES)
-(BOTH GASP)
(FEATHERINGHAMSTAN SCREAMS)
(FEATHERINGHAMSTAN GRUNTS)
(POWERING DOWN)
ALISHA: Buzz!
BUZZ: Now!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(FEATHERINGHAMSTAN SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(RUMBLING)
Move it, ranger!
(BUZZ GRUNTS)
Making our way back to the ship.
Come on, Buzz!
-Hurry!
-(FEATHERINGHAMSTAN WHIMPERS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
-(DOOR BEEPS)
-I'll go to the engine room.
-I'll take the helm.
-And I will...
BUZZ: Do nothing. I've got this.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE POWERS UP)
I.V.A.N.: How may I assist you?
Ugh! Autopilots.
Is there anything I can do, sir?
No and no! This is not a simulation.
Commander, status!
Fuel engaged. All systems go.
(ENGINE IGNITES)
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM BEEPING)
I.V.A.N.: Warning.
Launch trajectory unsound.
Come on. Come on. (GRUNTS)
I.V.A.N.: Collision imminent.
Abort. Abort.
-Abort...
-(RAPID BEEPING)
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
(GRUNTS)
Captain Lightyear, do you need my help?
-Negative.
-Are you sure?
I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
-(ENGINE WHINING)
-(ALARM WAILING)
(BUZZ STRAINING)
(CRASHES)
-(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
-(SOFT CRACKLING)
(AIR HISSES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
ALISHA: (SIGHS) It's bad, Buzz.
Our hyper-speed crystal
was totally destroyed.
Long story short, we're marooned.
I don't know.
What are you doing?
I'm court-martialing myself.
No, you're not.
Commander Hawthorne,
I hereby relieve myself
of all space ranger duties.
This was my fault,
and these people deserve better.
You can throw me in the brig.
Finish the mission, Buzz.
That's what we do.
We're not done until everyone gets home.
But we have no fuel crystal.
So we mine the resources on this planet.
Create a new crystal.
Crystallic fusion is highly unstable.
-Then we test it.
-No. It's too dangerous.
Manufacturing a crystal
capable of hyper speed
is like... like trying to lasso the sun.
And then someone would need
to attach that sun to a ship,
and then that ship needs someone to fly it
without blowing themselves into oblivion.
Who in their right mind would...
Oh!
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Buzz Lightyear mission log, stardate 3902.
After a full year of being marooned,
our specialized crew have put
this planet's vast resources
to incredible use.
Finally, our first hyper-speed
test flight is a go.
(CHEERING)
(BUG BUZZES)
-Ready, Captain Lightyear?
-(CHUCKLES)
Ready as I'll ever be,
Commander Hawthorne.
To infinity.
-BUZZ: And beyond.
-(ALISHA MIMICS EXPLOSION)
(EXCLAIMS, GRUNTS)
-Buzz!
-We got a breach in the perimeter.
Come on, I just...
Captain Lightyear!
-Airman Díaz.
-DÍAZ: Boy, (CHUCKLES)
the vines are a little feisty today, huh?
Are we ready to launch?
We're all ready if you are, sir.
A year of work for a four-minute flight.
-Isn't that something?
-Ha. Sure is.
BUZZ: Well, let's go find out
if this new hyper-speed fuel is stable,
so I can get us off this rock.
Ooh, almost forgot.
Here's your I.V.A.N., sir.
-Fully loaded.
-BUZZ: Ugh.
Autopilots.
And here, of course, is the XL-01.
Pretty sweet ride.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Now let's get you that fuel crystal.
ERIC: Good morning, Captain Lightyear.
Here is your specially formulated
fuel mixture.
So this is the fuel
that's gonna reach hyper speed?
ERIC: It has an 87.6% chance.
I'll take those odds.
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(POWERS UP)
Good luck, Captain. (GRUNTS)
We're all counting on you...
Airman.
(BUZZER BLARING)
XL-01 to mission control. Do you copy?
Copy, XL-01.
I'm gonna grant you
four minutes to be off-planet,
but then you come right back to us.
-(BUTTONS BEEP)
-That's an order.
Roger that.
Hyper speed, here I come.
CONTROL: T minus ten,
nine,
eight, seven,
six,
five, four,
three, two,
one. Launch.
(STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING)
-(SPACESHIP RATTLES)
-(ENGINE SLOWING)
I.V.A.N., pull up the flight plan, please.
I.V.A.N.: (GARBLED) Hello.
I am your... (INDISTINCT)
BUZZ: Ugh, autopilots.
(BLOWS)
I.V.A.N.: (CLEARLY) Hello,
I am your Internal
Voice-Activated Navigator.
Call me I.V.A.N.
Ready the flight plan, please, I.V.A.N.
I.V.A.N.: Certainly.
Your mission is to accelerate
through deep space,
slingshot around Alpha T'kani,
then through the deceleration rings
back here to T'kani Prime.
Target flight time, 4 minutes, 28 seconds.
CONTROL: XL-01,
you are clear for hyper launch.
Copy, Control. Initiating hyper launch.
(BEEPS)
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CRACKLING)
(TRILLS)
(ENGINES WHIRRING)
(BEEPS)
(MUSIC INTENSIFYING)
(BUZZES)
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
I.V.A.N.: Approaching 50% hyper speed.
(CRACKLING)
BUZZ: Fuel stable.
Increasing speed to 0.6c.
(WHOOSHING)
I.V.A.N.: 60% hyper speed.
Increasing speed to 0.7c.
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
I.V.A.N.: 70% hyper speed.
BUZZ: Fuel stable.
(STRAINED) Approaching 0.8c.
Pushing to hyper speed.
(ENGINE WHINING)
I.V.A.N.: Failure in engine one.
-Fuel cell unstable.
-I.V.A.N., status.
I.V.A.N.: Trajectory error,
plus four degrees.
Failure to course correct
will result in missing the rings.
We'll fly off into deep space,
resulting in certain death.
Yes, thank you.
I.V.A.N.: Ejection is your only option.
-(ALARM BEEPING)
-No, no. I can do it.
I.V.A.N.: Warning. You have
26 seconds to course correct.
You now have 25 seconds to course correct.
-You now have...
-Stop counting, please.
I.V.A.N.: I'm sorry. My safety protocols
prohibit me from terminating countdown.
Ugh, autopilots.
I.V.A.N.: Mission failure imminent,
please record your last words.
-(I.V.A.N. BEEPS)
-Not today, I.V.A.N.
(ON RECORDING) Not today, I.V.A.N.
I.V.A.N.: If you are satisfied
with this recording,
speak or select one.
I.V.A.N., push the engines all the way.
Maximum power.
I.V.A.N.: That action is inadvisable.
Fuel cell detonation...
Is exactly what I'm counting on.
(WHOOSHING)
-I.V.A.N.: Situation critical.
-(ALARM WAILING)
Fuel cell approaching peak capacity.
Open the fuel door, I.V.A.N.
I.V.A.N.: I'm sorry.
I didn't quite catch that.
-Please restate your command.
-Open fuel door!
I.V.A.N.: Detonation in five,
four, three,
two,
-one.
-Now!
(EXPLODES)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYS)
I.V.A.N.: Course corrected.
You failed to reach hyper speed.
(SIGHS) Didn't need to hear that, I.V.A.N.
I.V.A.N.: You didn't hear that.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll repeat.
-BUZZ: No, no. I heard.
-(SLOWLY) You failed to reach
-hyper speed.
-I meant I didn't need to...
-Thank you, I.V.A.N.
-You failed to reach...
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXCLAIMS)
-Commander, are you okay?
-BUZZ: Whoa.
Díaz, you... you grew a beard.
How did you grow a beard?
Oh, right. Uh...
First off, welcome back.
-Secondly...
-Wait.
Wait, what is this?
How long was I gone?
Four years, two months, and three days.
What?
Thought we'd lost you, Buzz.
Alisha, what happened?
-Time dilation.
-What?
ERIC: Time dilation is quite simple.
As you approached hyper speed,
your time slowed relative to our own.
So, during your mission,
you aged only minutes,
while the rest of us have aged years.
Simply put, the faster you fly...
The faster I fly,
the further into the future I travel.
I get it.
(SIGHS)
So, what are we gonna do now?
I don't know.
But I think we should hold off
on any more test flights
until we figure out something else.
Commander, we said finish the mission.
That's what space rangers do.
At what cost, Buzz?
Are you willing to lose
another four years?
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
So, everyone's just stuck here
because of me.
-(ENGINE POWERS DOWN)
-(BRAKES SQUEAK)
Hey. You all right?
Uh... Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
Wait, what's that?
Oh. I got engaged.
Oh, wow. That's...
That's great. What's her name?
Kiko. She's one of the science crew.
(CHUCKLES)
It's funny. I never would have met her
if we hadn't been stranded.
You got engaged to someone you just met?
Buzz, I met her three years ago.
Oh, right. Right. (CHUCKLES DRYLY)
Well, congratulations.
I'd love to meet her.
Well, there's plenty of time for that.
Get some rest.
That's an order.
(DOOR BEEPS)
Huh?
Uh...
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
-Hello, Buzz!
-(SCREAMS)
I am Sox. Your personal companion robot.
-My what?
-I was issued by Star Command
to ease your emotional transition
after your time away.
Oh.
Well, that's very considerate of you,
robot feline.
But no, thank you.
I'm afraid it's protocol.
Sensors indicate
you've missed four birthdays.
Would you like a frosted
snack cake to celebrate?
Negative. That would compromise
-my nutritional regimen.
-(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
(MUFFLED DING)
We can talk about your feelings.
I am an excellent listener.
No, no. Look, I've had a very long... day?
It did not go as planned.
The mission was unsuccessful?
Affirmative.
Oh, no. I am so sorry to hear that.
Thank you, Sox.
You're welcome, Buzz.
Shall we play a game?
BUZZ: No, thank you.
SOX: Are you sure?
I can create a game specifically for you
based on your exact personality profile.
Hey, listen. Sox, buddy, I'm pretty tired,
so I'm gonna go ahead and hit the rack.
Of course.
(SIGHS)
I can provide sleep sounds, if you like.
I have several options.
Summer night, ocean paradise, whale calls?
No, no. White noise is fine.
Very well.
-Good night, Sox.
-Good night, Buzz.
(MIMICKING WHITE NOISE)
(NOISE STOPS)
I.V.A.N.: Pull up. Pull up.
Pull up. Pull up.
Uh, Captain Lightyear,
do you need my help?
No. I can do it.
Buzz, are you sure?
I'm afraid it's protocol.
I can do it! (GASPING)
I can do it.
Sensors indicate you had a nightmare.
Would you like to talk about it?
Negative.
Okay. But remember,
my mission is to help you.
And I'm not giving up on my mission.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You know what, Sox?
I'm not giving up on my mission either.
SOX: Great! So, what can I do?
Well, why don't you engage
with your, um... your mouse buddy.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
Is there anything more challenging?
You want a challenge? Okay.
I guess you could work
on this fuel stability thing.
Crystallic fusion. Of course.
When should I expect you back?
About four years.
(DOOR BEEPS)
Hold on. You don't have to do this.
Commander, this is my mistake.
I need to make it right.
Okay. But maybe we should
think about this.
Think about what?
Come on, we're space rangers.
We finish the mission.
Well, it would be nice
to wear the suit again.
People are starting to forget
space rangers ever mattered.
Well, I'm about to fix that.
To infinity.
And beyond.
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
-(CRACKLING)
-(ALARM BEEPING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(HEROIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ALARM BEEPING)
-(CAR HORN HONKS)
-(TIRES SCREECH)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(MUSIC INTENSIFYING)
(BUZZ SCREAMS)
(MUSIC ENDS IN FLOURISH)
Hi, Buzz.
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
You'll be back here in a year or two,
and, well, I won't.
I don't know when it happened,
but I seem to have gone
and gotten very old. (CHUCKLES)
I always thought we'd get
to be space rangers again.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I miss being out among the stars.
All the adventures.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
But more than any of that,
(SIGHS) I missed you.
GIRL: Hi, Grandma.
Hey, sweetheart.
I'm leaving a message for my friend Buzz.
The space ranger?
ALISHA: (CHUCKLES) That's right.
He's in space right now.
Wow.
This is my granddaughter, Izzy.
I'm gonna be a space ranger, too.
Just like him?
(WHISPERS) Just like you.
(CHUCKLES)
(KISSES)
(CHOKES UP) Goodbye, Buzz.
I'm sorry I won't be there
to see you finish the mission.
(CRIES SOFTLY)
To infinity.
And beyond.
(ALISHA MIMICS EXPLOSION)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
Knock-knock. Sorry to interrupt.
I'm just movin' into my new... Oh!
(LAUGHS)
Look at that!
The actual Buzz Lightyear in the flesh.
Affirmative.
Commander Cal Burnside.
I was a big fan of yours when I was a kid.
Well, then I look forward
to working with you
to finally get us outta here.
Oh... (CHUCKLES) Did no one tell you?
Tell me what?
Yeah. Um...
(CLEARS THROAT)
That was the last mission, Buzz.
What?
We've decided we're gonna
go ahead and stay right here.
Wait, here? Negative.
That is not a viable option.
It is now. See, we're building this.
(DEVICE POWERS ON)
Laser-shield!
It'll keep all the critters out.
And we'll just tuck right in here
and make do with what we've got.
Make do? No, wait, wait,
but you don't understand, Commander.
I can still do it.
I can get us outta here.
Man, it's great you still believe that.
But we're good, Buzz.
Got the laser-shield.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
SOX: Oh. Hello, Buzz.
Buzz?
(BUZZ SIGHS)
Oh, well, I've got some good news, Buzz.
I figured out the fuel problem.
What?
It was an interesting combination.
Just the slightest variance,
(CHUCKLES) but it made all the difference.
Sox, how did you do this?
It took me 62 years, 7 months, and 5 days.
And it's stable?
Theoretically.
I look forward to finding out
on your next mission.
Yeah...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
What?
Evening, Captain.
We're here to pick up
your companion robot.
What do you mean?
OFFICER 2: Security purposes.
You understand.
No, actually, I don't.
Shutting down the program,
so we have to decommission your cat.
It'll just take a second.
Now, hold on. Just...
(SIGHS) At least let me do it.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(MUFFLED CRASHING)
(OFFICER 1 GRUNTS)
What?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS IN FRUSTRATION)
Uh, Buzz. Where are we going?
We're going to space.
What?
BUZZ: Buzz Lightyear
mission log, stardate...
I have no idea.
In possession of stable fuel formula.
I plan to reach hyper speed
and this time, finally finish the mission.
SOX: Uh, who you talking to?
Doesn't matter.
Buzz, my programming compels me
to notify Star Command
that you have gone...
Star Command was gonna decommission you.
-What?
-That's right.
Lights out. No more Sox.
Hey! You're not authorized
to be in this area...
(GRUNTS)
Whoa, I didn't know you could do that.
Wait a minute, was that for me?
In case I got out of line?
I bought you five minutes.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERING) All right, Sox.
-Give me the first one.
-Roger.
(TRILLING)
(BUTTONS BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
Okay. Here goes.
-(WHIRS)
-(EXPLOSION)
Whoa.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
-(GASPS) The formula!
-Shh, shh!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BEEPS, WHIRRING)
MAN: Tango to base. Tango to base.
Security breach in the launch bay.
Blast.
MAN: We have a guard down.
Repeat, we have a guard down.
(GASPS)
Okay.
-I.V.A.N.: (LOUDLY) Hello.
-No! No, wait! I.V.A.N.! No.
I.V.A.N.: I am your Internal
Voice-Activated Navigator.
-Shh! You hear that?
-Call me I.V.A.N.
Mission control,
activity detected in the XL-15.
-(SLURPING)
-Investigating.
Roger that.
Uh, XL-15, this is control.
Is there someone in there?
-Say something.
-CONTROL: XL-15,
please respond.
Copy, control. Uh, just the, um...
uh, cleaning crew. Cleaning crew.
We're cleaning the cockpit.
Cleaning items in here?
Uh, Commander, did we authorize
a cockpit cleaning for the XL-15?
What? No.
(STEAM HISSES)
(BUZZER BLARING)
-Stop! Stop! Come back!
-Hey! Wait!
XL-15, you are in violation
of Star Command protocol.
Cease your actions immediately.
-Open this hatch!
-(BUTTONS BEEP)
Commander, it's... it's Captain Lightyear.
Wait, what? Lightyear?
Well, get him outta there!
Stop right now and put
your hands over your head!
(BEEPS)
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(OFFICERS EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTS) Backup.
-We need backup.
-Get the Zap Patrol.
(ALARM WAILING)
SOLDIER: All right, team. Let's go.
(ALL GRUNT)
Override the silo doors.
He isn't going anywhere.
(DOORS POWER DOWN)
Blast.
I.V.A.N.: Unauthorized. Unauthorized.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-Unauthorized. Unauthorized.
-Just, come on, we're sitting ducks here!
Allow me.
Huh.
-Wait. What's happening?
-He...
-He overrode my override.
-How?
Beep-boop, beep-boop,
beep-boop, beep-boop.
(SOLDIER YELLS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOX GRUNTS)
Lightyear! Lightyear!
I know you can hear me.
Return the ship to base
right now, or so help me...
Sox, let's break this hyper-speed barrier
and get everyone home.
(CRACKLING)
(ENGINE ROARING)
(INTENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
I.V.A.N.: Approaching 70% hyper speed.
(CRACKLING)
Approaching 80% hyper speed.
-(BEEPING)
-BUZZ: Fuel stable.
(MUSIC INTENSIFYING)
I.V.A.N.: 90% hyper speed.
-(ELECTRICAL TRILL)
-(MUSIC STOPS)
(ELECTRICAL HUMMING)
(DISTORTED) 100% hyper speed.
(DEEP RUMBLING)
(BUZZ STRAINING)
(WHOOSHING)
(BUZZ YELLS)
Congratulations, Captain Lightyear.
You have achieved hyper speed.
(FANFARE PLAYS ON SPEAKER)
We did it. Sox, we did it!
Congratulations, Buzz.
That was utterly terrifying,
and I regret having joined you.
-(ALARM BUZZING)
-No, no, no.
What is it, Buzz?
Our velocity is still extremely high.
SOX: What? What? Oh, no!
Are we going to crash?
-No.
-(BUTTONS BEEPING)
Well, technically, yes. Just hang on.
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
-(PANTING)
-(ENGINE POWERING DOWN)
After all these years. Thank you, Sox.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
-Mission log, supplemental.
-(COUGHS)
After borrowing a ship from Star Command,
I've achieved hyper speed.
And I'm ready to finally leave
this planet once and for all.
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
-Come in, Star Command.
-(STATIC)
Star Command, come in.
Why don't they answer?
(GASPS) Hey, hey!
WOMAN: Shh. The robots.
(COUGHS) The what?
WOMAN: The robots.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MECHANICAL RUSTLING)
(MECHANICAL FOOTSTEPS)
BUZZ: Wait, what's it doing?
WOMAN: Shh.
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
-My ship!
-WOMAN: Be quiet.
Where'd it go?
WOMAN: Up there.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(POWERS UP)
(WHIRRING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
ROBOT LEADER: Where is the pilot?
What is that? What is going on?
WOMAN: Get down.
-(DISTANT THUD)
-Shoot! Come on.
They must've seen your ship land, too.
-Who?
-WOMAN: The robots.
Why are there robots?
Where did the robots come from?
WOMAN: Where did you come from?
-I came from here.
-WOMAN: Here? Wait.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Buzz?
BUZZ: Alisha?
Oh. Oh, no, that's my grandmother.
I'm Izzy.
Izzy?
But... But you were just a little...
Sox, how long were we gone?
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow.
22 years, 19 weeks, and 4 days.
Whoa.
Wait.
Come on.
In here.
Uh...
Thought I heard one.
-A robot?
-Yeah.
Hmm. Impressive.
Well, I am a Hawthorne.
You sure are.
You know, your grandma and I
could practically finish
each other's sentences.
If you're anything like her,
you and I are gonna make
-a great team.
-...some robots cry.
Okay... (CLEARS THROAT)
So, get me up to speed on this.
Right. The Zurg ship showed up
about a week ago.
What's a Zurg?
Oh, well, that's the only thing
the robots say,
so that's what we call the big ship.
The Zurg ship arrived,
the robots surrounded the base,
and then, well...
Citizens of T'kani Prime,
robot aliens have attacked.
Everyone, inside the perimeter.
-Look out!
-(WEAPON FIRES)
We are activating
the laser-shield immediately.
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
And that's the last we heard.
(MUFFLED LASER FIRE)
BUZZ: All those people,
they were counting on me,
and now they're trapped.
We've tried to reach them,
but there's no communication in or out.
Sox?
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow.
She's correct.
(SCOFFS) Did you just check me
against your cat?
Well, he's not your standard-issue feline.
Actually, Sox was
a gift from your grandmother.
-Hello, Izzy.
-Hello, Sox.
(SOX PURRS)
Hey, what's that noise?
Come on, don't break my cat.
He's purring. He likes it.
Sox, do you like that?
-I do.
-Huh.
Well, I hope you're ready for action.
Because all we needed was a pilot.
For what?
I have a plan, and I have a team.
Come on!
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC TEMPO SLOWS)
IZZY: All right, team. Fall in.
VOICES: Zap, zap!
BUZZ: Whoa.
I found a pilot.
Operation Surprise Party is a go!
I like this. An elite squad.
Best of the best.
You know, her grandmother
was the greatest space ranger
in the history of the corps.
It'll be an honor to work with you.
Come on, gather 'round, team.
Let's review our objectives.
WOMAN: Kill the robots.
MAN: And don't die.
WOMAN: "Don't die" is just something
you wanna do every day.
MAN: It's still an objective.
If I may, we have one objective.
We need to put this crystal in the turnip
and get outta here.
So, to do that,
we have to get onto the base.
WOMAN: To do that,
we have to kill all the robots.
To do that, we have
to destroy the Zurg ship.
MAN: And to do any of that,
we have to not die.
(CLEARS THROAT) DERIC.
DERIC: Allow me to explain
Operation Surprise Party.
It's a variation
on Operation Thunder Spear.
Didn't you get a medal for that one?
Two, actually, but, uh...
Wait, how do you know
about Operation Thunder Spear?
(CHUCKLES) I've read all my
grandma's space ranger books
from cover to cover.
Twice.
-(BUTTONS BEEPING)
-BUZZ: Huh.
DERIC: Excuse me, robot kitty-cat.
Oh, sorry.
DERIC: Sensors have indicated
that the Zurg ship
powers the robots on the ground.
So, we fly up there, we blow up the ship.
And surprise, robots!
You're toast.
Then, we put your crystal in the turnip...
And finish the mission.
It's a good plan. To infinity.
Are you trying to get me
to pull your finger?
MAN: Don't fall for it.
No, not like that, it was...
(SIGHS) Sorry, it's a thing
your grandma and I used to do.
WOMAN: Ew.
I... We would never...
She didn't mean to...
Anyway, forget it. Moving on.
Let's load these munitions
into the Armadillo
and steel ourselves for combat.
Operation Surprise Party is on!
Buzz, uh, do you hear that?
I hear something.
You think it's a robot?
MAN: Nah, we've never seen a robot
this far from the base.
I don't hear anything.
-(GRUNTS)
-Oh. Now I do!
(GRUNTING)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
-(BEEPING)
-BUZZ: Did you... Get the...
-Don't worry, we got you!
-(SOX MEOWS)
(WEAPON WHIRS, FIRES)
-(ROBOT CHIRPS)
-What?
Ugh! Fear not!
The junior patrol has your back.
The junior what?
(GRUNTS)
No! The ship!
(BUZZ GRUNTS)
(TRILLS)
(MEOWS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
-MAN: Did I get it?
-Pretty close.
Sorry, I'm not trained with this weapon.
Let me reload it.
Not trained? Wait,
what do you mean, you're not trained?
(SOX SNARLS, GRUNTS)
(SOX GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
You... You there! Grab it! Grab it!
WOMAN: Grab what?
Oh. I'm not allowed to handle weapons.
Be a violation of my parole.
-Parole?
-Buzz!
Izzy! Now!
(GRUNTS) No!
Okay, new plan.
New plan? What was the old plan?
I need the...
Has anyone seen the harpoons?
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
(BEEPING)
They came preloaded with a harpoon,
but I can't find...
Oh, no, here, I found them.
Don't worry, I found the harpoons,
I'm gonna reload it now. Check this out.
(SOX GRUNTING)
(ROBOT LEADER GROANS)
-MAN: Did I get it?
-A little to the left.
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS, GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
-Ha-ha!
-(POWERS DOWN)
What? (GRUNTS)
(ROBOT SHORT-CIRCUITS)
-MAN: Did I get it?
-You got it!
Yes!
-Ha-ha. Boom!
-(BUZZ SIGHS)
-(SYSTEM BUZZES)
-(GROANS IN FRUSTRATION)
(SCREAMS)
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRILLS)
Okay, okay... What exactly...
How did that...
Who are you?
We're the junior patrol at your service.
Right. I'm gonna need more information.
We're a volunteer team
of self-motivated cadets.
We train one weekend a month
here at the outpost.
Mo and Darby and I
were the first to arrive last weekend
when the robots showed up.
So, we cooked up Operation Surprise Party.
So you're rookies?
Oh, boy. We'd love to be rookies.
Still building up to that.
(SIGHS) Okay.
Do you have munitions training?
-Partial.
-Tactical engagement?
-Pending.
-Combat experience?
Yes! If you count the robot situation
we just went through.
Okay. Come on, Sox.
What are you doing?
Look, you seem like nice people.
I'm very supportive
of your training initiatives.
But I'm gonna go ahead
and take it from here.
We just saved you from that robot.
-Excuse me?
-Mo made the kill shot.
Mo got lucky.
Heh. Very.
BUZZ: So, if you could just point me
in the direction of another ship...
DERIC: There are operational spacecraft
at the abandoned storage depot.
Great. Where's that?
DERIC: The storage depot
is directly adjacent
to the Resource Reconstituting Center,
which is 4.2 kilometers
from your current location.
Great. Where's that?
DERIC: It's actually quite simple.
-Okay...
-(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
DERIC: You will first head south,
towards the base.
After two stoplights, you will...
Wait. That is not right.
That is a dead end.
Oh, I see. I was in the wrong spot.
Apologies. I will start over.
You will first head south,
towards the base.
After two stoplights,
you'll take a gentle left, and...
Shoot. I have made another error.
-(BUZZ SIGHS IN FRUSTRATION)
-We'll just show you.
DERIC: Allow me to restart.
You will first head south,
towards the base.
After two stoplights,
you'll take a hard right.
BUZZ: Buzz Lightyear
supplemental mission log.
Having finally achieved hyper speed,
I now have an additional obstacle
in my way.
In order to flee this planet,
I'll have to destroy
a massive alien ship alone
with no assistance of any kind.
You know, we could help you.
It is our plan.
-I can't allow that.
-(BEEPS)
Star Command code 2709.3
forbids me from placing
unqualified personnel
in harm's way.
Okay. But I'm a Hawthorne.
It's more than just a name, Izzy.
You have to know exactly how...
...know what you're gonna say next.
...to react in every situation.
Oh, thought I had that one.
Okay. And you,
you're in a correctional situation
of some kind?
Parole program.
I do this, and they shave
a little time off my sentence.
But I really learned a lot in there.
Darby can take any three things
and make 'em explode.
BUZZ: Okay. And what about you?
Me? Oh, well, I thought this was gonna be
like a fun boot camp-workout thing,
but it is not,
so I was actually coming out here
to turn in my stuff, and...
He's a quitter.
-(SCOFFS) I'm not a quitter.
-You were quitting.
What are you talking about?
I was just going
in a different direction...
Yeah, the direction of a quitter.
(GASPS) You know what? I give up.
-(CHUCKLES) See?
-Oh, on your right.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
DERIC: Now, where was I?
Ah, here we are. Let me back up.
Hey, keep workin' on your skills.
It's the only way to get better.
We can help you.
And I appreciate that.
Just go back to your training facility.
Stay alert, stay safe.
I'm going to commandeer
this P-32 Armadillo
and go blow up the Zurg ship.
So, this is just goodbye?
Affirmative. Goodbye.
Sorry, I forgot my cat.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYS)
(SOFT CHITTERING)
Life forms detected.
What are they?
-Giant insectoid organisms.
-Ugh.
This building appears to be
some sort of hive.
Are they a threat?
Sensors indicate they are hibernating.
Very good.
Oh, look.
It's the XL-01.
It's been a long time since...
-Whoa!
-What is it?
Come on. I'll show you.
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS) Finally.
(GRUNTING)
-(BUZZ YELPS)
-Sorry to interrupt.
Looks like you were having
a real nice moment.
What are you doing here? It's not safe.
You took the keys to our truck.
Oh, there they are.
-Whoa.
-(KEY FOB BEEPS)
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALL GASP)
-Come on, come on.
-(KEY FOB CLICKING)
-Shh! Quiet.
-I'm trying! (WHIMPERS)
-(KEY FOB BEEPS)
-Ha! Got it.
(LOW GROWLING)
-(SHRIEKS)
-(SCREECHING)
-Oh! Somebody get the...
-Get the door!
(GRUNTS) Ha! You were
gonna say "Get the door,"
and I got the door. (GASPS)
Well, I'm gonna be blunt here.
I wish that hadn't happened.
So do the rest of us.
Everyone grab a weapon.
Boy, I'd love to, but my parole...
As a Star Command officer,
I grant you emergency authority.
We're gonna blast our way outta here.
Now we're talkin'!
Buzz, the probability of surviving
a frontal attack is 38.2%.
Seems a bit low.
What about stealth mode?
How do you know about stealth mode?
Grandma and I used to play
stealth mode all the time.
It was like hide-and-seek.
But with a twist.
Okay, well, it's actually good thinking.
I'll use stealth mode to disorient them.
Or, and stick with me here,
we could all use stealth mode
and just walk right out.
-DARBY: Oh, ho-ho!
-(MO GRUNTS)
You mean you would wear
space ranger suits?
This one already has my name on it.
(GROANS)
Okay.
Let's review.
-I'm going...
-OTHERS: That way.
-And you're going...
Okay. Very good.
Check it out. I'm Feathers...
Feather... Feathering... Oh.
Oh, look. A pen. Cool.
-Does yours have a pen?
-Okay. Pay attention.
Stealth mode is fairly simple.
There are just two parts.
You press the button...
-Is it this button?
-I will tell you which button.
-Mm. What about this button?
-I'm sorry.
We're not gonna have time
to go over all the buttons.
Okay, forget the button.
What about this thing?
-It's more of a pull...
-No! No, no, no!
That's the Surrender String.
You never pull that.
There is no more shameful maneuver
for a space ranger.
DARBY: Excuse me.
Did I miss which button
is the stealth mode button?
It's this button.
Not yet.
You push this button,
then you go out the front door,
and I'll go blow up the Zurg ship.
-Ready?
-OTHERS: Ready.
No, wait. Not ready. Hang on.
Okay. Got 'em. (CHUCKLES)
That would've been embarrassing.
Okay.
Goodbye again.
(BUZZ SPUTTERING)
Um, Sox, you're inhibiting my visual.
Oh, sorry. Is this better?
-Negative.
-Okay. How about this?
How about this?
-(BUG CHITTERS)
-SOX: Heh. (EXHALES)
BUZZ: Okay. Here we go.
(BEEPING)
Very good.
Stealth mode working as planned.
MO: (CHUCKLES) This is pretty cool.
These dumb bugs can't even see us.
DARBY: Uh-uh.
MO: Hey, bug. Hey, bug, bug!
I'm right here, bug. Can't you see me?
(MO LAUGHS)
He can't. He can't see me at all.
-(DEVICE BEEPING)
-BUZZ: And time has elapsed.
-(POWERING DOWN)
-(GASPS) Wait, the timer.
They don't know about the timer.
DARBY: (IN SINGSONG) Na-na, na-na, na-na.
You can't see me.
-(LAUGHS)
-Wait. I can see you.
I can see you, too.
(GASPS) The bugs can see us.
No, no, no, no. I surrender! (GASPS)
-(BUGS SCREECHING)
-IZZY: Whoa!
-(GRUNTS)
-(MO SCREAMING)
DARBY: (GRUNTING) Back! Get back!
(MO CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Ahh! This isn't working.
You have to keep going.
We have to turn around.
(MO CONTINUES SCREAMING)
They're headed right for us.
No, no, do not approach the vehicle!
-(BUGS SCREECHING)
-(ALL SCREAM)
Ugh. (GRUNTING)
(MO WHIMPERS)
-(DOOR BANGING)
-(BUZZ PANTING)
IZZY: All right!
-Way to adapt, team.
-Get it up here.
Why are you congratulating yourselves?
(SCOFFS) Because I just Hawthorned us
right outta that situation.
But you could've made it if...
If you had told us stealth mode wears off.
-Well...
-(DOOR THUDS)
-(SCREECHING)
-Okay, everyone just strap in.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
I.V.A.N.: Hello, I am your...
BUZZ: Hold on.
(NERVOUSLY) Are we going to space?
No, I'm going to drop you somewhere.
(MO AND IZZY SCREAMING)
That was a big swirly-do.
Oh, I think I need a bag.
No, no, do not vomit inside the vehicle.
I can see stars. That is space.
What is happening right now?
She's afraid of space.
-What?
-She should be. It's horrible.
Izzy, remember your exercises.
-(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
-Uh, it's coming.
No, no, no. Engage your helmet.
That'll catch it.
-Buzz? We got a ship!
-Izzy, I'm trying to...
(SOX SHOUTS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHT TRILLS)
(SIGHT BEEPING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
I can't see anything.
Oh, no! The dark side of the planet.
Oh! Over there!
(SPLUTTERS) 10 o'clock!
Hold on. This isn't gonna be pretty.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL PANTING)
-Is everyone okay?
-IZZY: I think so.
(WHOOSHING)
(SIGHS)
BUZZ: Sox, get me a damage report.
SOX: One moment, please.
Beep-boop, beep-boop,
beep-boop, beep-boop.
IZZY: (SIGHS) Okay. This is better.
This is better?
No, obviously this is worse overall.
I just meant, you know...
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
How are you afraid of space?
(CHUCKLES) Oh, it's pretty easy.
Did you know if you let go out there,
you just keep goin' in the same direction?
Forever. Just... (IMITATES WHOOSHING)
Well, then how were you going
to blow up the Zurg ship?
Oh, I woulda been ground support.
(GROANS)
I know, Grandma wasn't afraid of space.
No, because she was a space ranger.
Astrophobia is
an automatic disqualification.
What was that thing?
-I don't know.
-Well, is it gonna come back?
I don't know.
But how did it... Okay, you don't know.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
I was done. I finally had the crystal.
This was supposed to be over.
But who am I kidding?
I don't need a crystal.
I need a time machine
to get outta this mess.
Ping! Assessment complete.
BUZZ: How bad is it?
SOX: The blast was absorbed
by the heat shield
and only caused a minor electrical short.
Okay.
So, in order to be flight operational,
the Armadillo will require
a material of specialized capacitance.
Oh, like an electrical thingy.
How do you know that?
We learned this.
Specialized capacitance?
Remember, we built
those field radios last month?
Oh, yeah. That was fun.
Yeah, except Darby messed hers up.
I'm gonna mess you up.
Please. I'm trying to think here.
(WHISPERS) I messed mine up,
but then I fixed it.
Yeah, but you broke that computer console.
I needed that little coil for its...
What was it?
Specialized capacitance...
Hey, honestly,
there is a lot of room out here.
If you guys wanna reminisce,
you could go over there.
Or, look, there's no one
trying to think over there.
(GASPS) We can go up there.
BUZZ: Fine. Perfect.
Yes. Okay, new plan.
-(DARBY GROANS)
-Wait, what?
That mining facility
will have a console, right?
That console will have
a little coil thing, right?
And that little coil thing
will have the...
MO: Specialized capacitance.
That we need to fix the ship. Right?
SOX: She's right.
BUZZ: Huh.
Good job.
Now that's thinking like a Hawthorne.
Let's go get that part and get outta here
before that thing finds us again.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoa.
IZZY: Over there.
BUZZ: Okay, here we go.
-(BUZZING)
-MO: Huh?
(MO GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
In order to repair our ship,
we have to find some way
to get inside the command center and...
Oh.
Nice job, elderly convict.
(DOOR BEEPS)
Okay. The activation coil
should be in here.
Sox?
Need a pen?
SOX: And, got it.
Okay, yeah. Another time.
-(BUTTON CLICKS)
-(ALARM BEEPING)
-Oh, no.
-(ALARM WAILING)
AI: Security measures activated.
-(IZZY AND MO YELP)
-No! Not this again.
Not what? What is this?
A capture cone. It holds ya
until they come and get ya.
No one's coming to get us.
They're all trapped on the base.
So we should just leave, right?
We can't just leave.
Sure we can. Take it from me,
you can always just leave.
Look. See? (CHUCKLES)
-(THUD)
-Come on! (GRUNTING)
DARBY: Told you.
Now, be careful, because these things...
(ANGRILY) combine if they touch.
All right, sorry.
But maybe if we both try it?
That's not gonna work.
(SIGHS) You haven't even tried.
(DARBY SIGHS)
-(MO AND DARBY GRUNT)
-IZZY: No, no, no!
Oh, meow!
(DOOR BEEPS)
Yeah, that didn't work.
-Buzz?
-Whoa, whoa, hold on.
I'm no help to anyone if
I'm stuck in there with you.
Sox, can you turn these off?
(GRUNTS) I can't reach the controls.
(SIGHS)
Wait, there's a soft spot
in the floor here.
-Maybe we can...
-That's my foot. (GRUNTS)
IZZY: Sorry.
BUZZ: Hey. Whoa. Watch it!
(CRACKLING)
Wait, that's it.
That thing powers these things.
-Then let's hit it again.
-Wait, wait, wait.
We need the door to be open.
So I'll open this,
you slam into the power source,
these things will disappear,
and we'll walk right out.
IZZY: Yes, sir.
MO: Okay.
Ready?
(DOOR BEEPS)
-(ALL GRUNTING)
-Keep trying!
(DOOR BEEPS)
-(SIGHS)
-We're just not heavy enough.
Buzz, we need you.
Wait, in there?
But if it doesn't work,
I won't be able to save you.
You don't need to save us.
You need to join us.
(GRUNTS)
-(ALL GRUNTING)
-Again.
ALL: Again!
-(DOOR BEEPS)
-Again!
-(ALL GRUNT)
-(BLASTING)
-BUZZ: No!
-Go, go!
-(IZZY AND MO SCREAM)
-IZZY: Watch out!
-(MO GASPING)
SOX: Uh... (YELPS)
Buzz, no!
BUZZ: We need the coil. (GRUNTING)
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDING UP)
-(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
-(BUZZ BREATHING SHAKILY)
We got you.
(BOTH GRUNT)
(PANTING)
Oh, look. Snacks.
Anyone go for a snack?
Mm.
(MO CHUCKLES)
(VENDING MACHINE CLATTERS)
Here. Let's all recharge a little.
-(SOX CHARGING)
-Here you go.
Huh. This is, uh... What, uh... What's...
What's happenin' here?
Somethin' wrong with your sandwich?
Why's the...
Why's the meat on the outside?
'Cause it's a sandwich?
No, the bread is supposed to be
on the outside.
What, like bread, meat, bread?
That's too much bread.
Yeah, but this is all wet.
Yeah. Juicy fingers. That's the best part.
When's the last time you had a sandwich?
I don't know, 100 years ago? Give or take.
(CHUCKLES) This guy. "Bread, meat, bread."
It's too much bread.
That would just suck all the moisture
-out of your mouth.
-(IZZY AND MO LAUGH)
Good one, Darby.
-Oh, no!
-(GASPS) Sox!
Wake up, Sox.
Come on, little buddy. Come back to me.
Please, Sox, I'm sorry.
Sox.
(COUGHS) Hello. I... I require a reboot.
(ALL SIGH IN RELIEF)
-(SOX CHARGING)
-(MO SIGHS)
I'm sorry, guys. I almost killed Sox.
I almost got us all killed back there.
Hey. Listen to me. It was just a mistake.
Right, Buzz?
Oh, uh...
Just, you know, try to be a little better.
(MO SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Listen.
Um...
I just, uh...
When I first went to the academy,
I was not, you know, good.
(CHUCKLES DRYLY)
I screwed up. Every day.
I got tangled in the obstacle course,
my hands shook so much
I couldn't hit the target.
Not the bull's-eye, the whole target.
And I was gonna quit after the first week.
It was clear I was not
space ranger material.
Really?
Yeah.
But her grandma saw something in me.
So, I started looking for it, too.
-SOX: Recalibrating.
-(GASPS)
(ELECTRONIC WARBLING)
One corrupted file restored.
Uh... Hey, he's lighting up.
-Grandma...
-Hello, Sox.
I need you to do me a favor.
I need you to look after my best friend.
His name's Buzz.
He's away right now,
but he'll be back soon.
He's a space ranger.
He's going to get us all home.
Get us all home...
(EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BUZZ SIGHS)
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
What's wrong?
Did you not hear that?
She believed I could fix
the mistake I made.
And that belief cost her everything.
Everything? No.
She had Grandma Kiko,
my dad and me, all her friends.
She didn't mean to be here,
but she had a whole life
on this planet, Buzz.
All of us have.
Except for you.
We wanted to be space rangers again.
-We wanted to matter.
-(CHUCKLES)
Believe me. She mattered.
(EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUES)
Hmm. You know, it is pretty good this way.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah? Bread, meat, bread.
How long did you do it like that?
(CHUCKLES) Forever.
Ping!
Ah, fully recharged.
Come on.
Let's go put this part in the ship
and get out of here.
Sox, can you light our way?
Of course. Click-click.
Click-click.
Ha! I see you. I'm gonna
get you. I'm gonna get you.
Oh, I didn't get you.
-Uh, Sox?
-Where'd you go? I got you!
BUZZ: Sox.
SOX: Oh, yeah, sorry.
(CHUCKLES) This is exciting.
Operation Surprise Party, here we come!
Wait, what? Negative.
I can't put you in harm's way like that.
What, are you gonna
do the whole mission alone?
I can do it.
Uh, because you got
a Hawthorne right here.
And I appreciate that.
Tell you what,
I'll let you know if I need you.
But until then, let's just try to get back
to the Armadillo without any more trouble.
(ALL YELL)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
-(BUZZ GASPS)
-(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS) Run!
-(ALL GRUNT)
-(IZZY GASPS)
-No!
-(MO GASPS)
What? It's after me. Go back to the ship.
But... But, Buzz!
(GRUNTING AND PANTING)
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
I'm being pursued by a... uh...
Just a massive robot.
I'm leading it away while
the others escape to the ship.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(STRAINING)
(WEAPON WHIRRING)
Buzz.
(GASPS) What? How do you know my name?
Come with me.
-What?
-(WEAPON WHIRS)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS) This is definitely
a violation of my parole.
(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
IZZY: Come on. Let's get outta here.
(TRILLING)
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
Ready yourselves for launch.
Operation Surprise Party is back on.
-What? With us?
-(SWITCHES CLICKING)
What, am I gonna do
the whole mission alone?
-(CONSOLE BEEPING)
-We can't launch yet.
I need five minutes to install the coil.
(ROBOT CHIRPS)
We can't sit here for five minutes.
The ship still has hover capabilities.
Then let's use 'em.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
We might lose 'em in the fire geysers.
Point the way. You two, blast some robots.
But we haven't even finished
our munitions training.
Shh. How hard can it be? Look.
We got these spikey things,
and these ones probably explode.
Just do whatever feels right.
What? What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna dance with Mr. Boom.
Now that's satisfying.
20% complete.
Out of 100?
(CLANGING)
They're gaining on us.
Where are those fire geysers?
IZZY: Dead ahead.
Don't worry, I know every last inch of...
-Watch out!
-(ALARM BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Here. Throw this.
-Wait, wait. Hold on.
-Throw it!
(SCREAMS)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
Fire geysers dead ahead!
BUZZ: Whoa. Whoa!
Uh, 50% complete.
-(BOTH SCREAM)
-ROBOT: B-Zurg.
(BOTH GRUNT)
Hey! We have explosives back here.
(ROBOT CHIRPS)
Quick! Give me something.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
90% complete.
Izzy, do you know how to
transfer power on the fly?
Uh, I've done it in the simulator.
Well, it's about to get real.
Do you need my help with anything?
Absolutely not.
95% complete.
Ready thrusters. Green button. Middle.
Done.
Remember from training.
You don't pull the trigger,
you squeeze the trigger.
(SCOFFS) I know.
-Uh, 99% complete.
-Transfer to
-oscillating power.
-Oscillating power. Done.
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
-(SIGHT BEEPS)
-SOX: 100% complete.
Ugh. Reboot. Okay, be ready to launch
-once the fuel cell is...
-Ready launch!
BUZZ: No!
(DARBY GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(ALARM BUZZING)
-IZZY: Oh, no.
-Blast!
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS) Grab the crystal!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
No.
I...
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
Buzz.
I'm so sorry.
Everything was happenin' so fast, and I...
I just...
(SIGHS)
I made a mistake.
Yeah.
Okay. But we're not done, right?
We can still do something.
Izzy, look around.
There is nothing to do.
The mission... (SIGHS)
It's over.
Buzz.
Buzz!
Where are you going?
I just need to (SIGHS) be by myself.
-(GASPS, YELLS)
-No!
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Buzz!
Buzz?
(MUFFLED RUMBLING)
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS, GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
What the...
What is this? Where are we?
Who are you?
Now, that's the question.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC BUILDS UP)
Huh?
You look good, Buzz.
Dad?
(CHUCKLES) Guess again.
Huh?
(METAL CLINKS)
Sox?
(DISTORTED) Hello, Buzz.
I don't understand.
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
I messed this all up.
Hey. It was just a mistake.
Remember what you told me?
This one's different.
Why?
Because it's mine!
(SIGHS)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm supposed to be as good as my grandma.
I'm supposed to be a Hawthorne.
But I'm not.
(ELECTRONIC WARBLING)
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYING)
Buzz?
Wait a minute. Hold on.
You're not me. I'm me.
Well, you're you now.
But I'm you 50 years from now.
Well, there can't be two mes.
Yet here we both are.
Okay, then. If you're me,
I'm thinking of a number
between one and...
Twelve hundred and seventy-three.
BUZZ: Whoa.
-(BUZZ GASPS)
-ROBOT: B-Zurg.
Isn't that cute?
Robots can't quite say "Buzz,"
so around here, I'm just Zurg.
-ROBOT: B-Zurg.
-And I guess so are you.
How? I don't understand.
Don't worry about it.
None of this is gonna matter.
OLD SOX: Buzz.
BOTH: Yes?
You have to explain it all to him.
(SIGHS) You're right.
I'm sorry. It's just exciting.
You're finally here.
See, I reached hyper speed, too.
I.V.A.N.: Hyper speed.
OLD BUZZ: Just like you did.
But I wasn't greeted as a hero.
No, that new commander was gonna arrest me
for stealing the XL-15.
I'd found a way to get them home,
and they didn't even care.
So, I escaped.
I went as far as I could
as fast as I could.
At that speed for that long,
I traveled centuries.
And I ended up in a future
you wouldn't recognize,
filled with technology you can't imagine.
And that's when it dawned on me.
If we can use this crystal
to go forward in time,
why not use it to go back?
But we can't go back in time.
-We can now.
-What?
Listen, Buzz. I've broken time.
What's happening to you
never happened to me.
This is a new now that's never been lived.
You see, we can change things, Buzz.
Well, if we can go back in time,
we can... we can stop ourselves
from ever landing on that planet.
From ever hitting that mountain.
We can just continue the mission home.
And none of this will have ever happened.
BOTH: It's a good plan.
And this crystal is the key to it all.
Wait, don't you already have one?
OLD BUZZ: Well, sort of.
See, I wore my crystal out
testing the time travel.
Wore myself out, too. It took a while.
Turns out, this isn't an exact science.
This is as far back in time
as I could get.
Come on. (CHUCKLES)
Help me configure the engine.
It should look familiar.
Wait, is this...
is this based on the turnip?
Set it for reverse thrusters, full.
-(POWERING UP)
-So, we designed all of this?
OLD BUZZ: Oh, no,
this is all, uh, borrowed.
I just made some modifications.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
She'll get to be
a space ranger again, Buzz.
-Yeah.
-(SWITCHES CLICKING)
-Although...
-What?
Well, she won't have her family.
She won't have Izzy.
Who's Izzy?
Look, she's not gonna miss anyone
if she never meets them
in the first place, right?
The only thing people are gonna know
is that we finished our mission.
Here. Hand me your crystal.
Buzz?
I don't know, maybe... (SIGHS)
Maybe we should think about this.
Think about what?
Commander Hawthorne believed
we could fix this mistake we made.
And that belief cost her everything.
Oh, no. No, no. We had that all wrong.
She had a whole life down there.
What kind of life?
We're supposed to be space rangers.
We're supposed to matter.
You don't wanna live like this, Buzz.
Waking up with that same nightmare,
haunted by your mistake.
But you can finally let go of that.
Starting right now.
You're right.
I can.
Where you going?
You and me, we're not the same.
I'm sorry.
No, Buzz.
(MENACING MUSIC PLAYS)
(SIGHS) Hey, Cat.
Do you know how to fly this thing?
SOX: Um, there's no fuel.
See? This is why we should never
have gotten in over our heads.
DARBY: What did you wanna do?
Wait at the outpost
until the robots found us?
MO: Well, that's better
than being stranded out here
where no one's ever gonna find us.
(GROANS) You are the last
person I wanna be stuck with
in a life-and-death situation.
Well, you're in luck, okay?
'Cause look around.
This is just a "death" situation.
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow, meow.
(SIGHS) I've completely lost Buzz.
He's too far away to track.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(GASPS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC BUILDING UP)
-Everybody! Inside!
-What?
Get inside the ship.
(WHIMPERS) What's after us now?
DARBY: We don't have any more weapons.
It's okay. We're getting outta here.
SOX: Where are we going?
We're goin' to space.
-Hey! Let go of me. No!
-(ROBOT CHIRPS)
I don't understand
what's happening here, Buzz.
You've changed.
And not for the better. (CHUCKLES)
No!
You can't do this.
You're gonna erase it all.
OLD BUZZ: (CHUCKLES) Exactly.
No, you're gonna take away everything.
People's families, their friends.
My friends.
They have lives on that planet.
Everyone does.
Except for us.
OLD BUZZ: (SIGHS)
I hardly recognize you, Buzz.
All these new ideas...
You know what?
We'll go ahead and erase those, too.
-(DART WHOOSHES)
-(OLD BUZZ GROANS)
-BUZZ: Whoa!
-I bought you five minutes.
-Why?
-I like this new you.
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
We have to destroy this ship.
Can you get me to the bridge?
Certainly. Follow me.
(ROBOT CHIRPS)
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
Operation Surprise Party, here we go.
Zap, zap!
We need to protect our escape ship.
So don't let any robots
come through that door.
Don't worry. We'll seal it off.
You go find Buzz.
I'll track the chip in his dog tags.
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow. Hmm.
What's wrong?
Uh, I'm getting two Buzz signals.
That can't be right.
I'll triangulate.
That'll get us close enough. Come on.
A shortcut back.
(MO GRUNTS, GASPS)
Whoop. (GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Oh.
Well, that's pretty neat.
-We have to go.
-Yep, all right.
(STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR BEEPS)
Ugh, great.
I don't know any of these controls.
-Wait. I.V.A.N.?
-I.V.A.N.: Yes, Captain?
Boy, am I glad to see you.
Initiate self-destruct sequence
in two minutes.
I.V.A.N.: You got it.
Self-destruct countdown initiated.
Buzz, you don't want
any of this cool technology?
-Only you, buddy. Come on.
-(ALARM WAILING)
-OLD BUZZ: Traitor!
-No! (GRUNTS)
OLD BUZZ: Enough.
Just tell me where the crystal is.
MO: Okay, we've got
to protect our escape ship.
So how do we close this door?
I don't know.
What? You said,
"Don't worry, we'll seal it off."
Right. So, don't worry. We will.
Ah. Here we go.
Look. See?
-(BEEPING)
-What?
-(POWERS DOWN)
-(ALARM BUZZING)
(MO GASPS)
(ROBOTS' FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow, meow.
Oh! The signal is tighter now.
He has to be straight this way.
IZZY: (SHUDDERS) That's a lot of space.
Keep it together.
-Keep it together.
-(DOOR BEEPS)
(GASPS) No, no, no!
(SIGHS)
I don't understand.
The signal says Buzz is 50 meters away.
(GASPS) He's over there.
You think we're not the same, Buzz?
You're already me.
You just don't know it yet.
I'm never gonna be you!
Well, if you're not gonna be me,
you're not gonna be anyone.
-(GRUNTS)
-(POWERING DOWN)
I.V.A.N.: Artificial gravity disengaged.
Blast.
No, no, no, no.
OLD BUZZ: Ha-hah!
(ROBOT CHIRPS)
-Hey, what are you doing?
-Building a bomb.
Oh, nice. Do you need a pen?
No. Here.
Aw, thank you.
Mm, peppermint.
Give me the wrapper.
So, you can just build a bomb
out of that stuff?
I've worked with less.
Now give me the gum.
Wait. I'm not done.
There's still a lot of flavor left.
Come on!
There. When they step on it,
it'll blow up.
What if they don't step on it?
I mean, I wouldn't step on that.
Would you?
(SIGHS) Then we need to drop
something heavy on it.
(BUZZ GRUNTING)
BUZZ: Just gonna...
OLD BUZZ: No!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS, SIGHS)
(ALARM WAILS)
-Buzz?
-(GROANS)
ALISHA: Buzz!
Alisha?
Are you okay?
No. I... I can't do it alone. I need help.
Buzz. I'm not my grandma.
Izzy, I don't need your grandma.
I need you.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Sox. How do we get over there?
Through the airlock.
Through there? There's nothing out there.
Exactly. Nothing in your way.
You just go straight across.
No!
(ALARM BUZZING)
Let me get this straight,
when this falls on your bomb,
-it'll definitely explode?
-Yes.
-And that'll seal the door?
Well, we better hurry.
I am hurrying. (PANTS)
Why don't you hurry?
-(GRUNTING) Come on.
-(SHRIEKS)
(ROBOTS APPROACHING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GASPS)
Okay.
IZZY: (WHISPERING)
Come on, come on, Izzy, come on.
You got this. (GASPING)
(FEEBLY) Oh, man.
Oh, no.
Uh, just don't look down.
Or up. It's all space.
It's everywhere. All around you.
I'm sorry. I'm probably not helping.
Just go straight.
Once you push off,
that's the direction you'll go.
IZZY: But what if I miss?
Don't miss.
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDING UP)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(IZZY BREATHING DEEPLY)
(ALARMS SOUNDING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIRRING)
IZZY: Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
-Whoa!
-(IZZY YELLS)
-(GRUNTING)
-Sox!
SOX: Whoa. Whoa, whoa!
-(SOX SCREAMS)
-(IZZY GRUNTING)
-Thank you, Izzy.
-(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
-(DOOR BEEPS)
-(IZZY GRUNTS)
There's no way in.
SOX: Perhaps I could help.
(HAWKING)
(ALARM WAILING)
-You can't hide from me, Buzz.
-(BUZZ GRUNTS)
It's like hiding from yourself.
I'll always find you.
-(GRUNTS)
-(WEAPON WHIRS, DIES)
(OLD BUZZ CHUCKLES)
(ROBOT CHIRPS)
(MO YELPS)
(OLD BUZZ CHUCKLES)
I.V.A.N.: Manual override activated.
(CRACKLING)
(WEAPON WHIRS)
OLD BUZZ: Huh?
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
-IZZY: Buzz!
-Now!
(OLD BUZZ GROANS)
Come on, let's get outta here.
We have to blow up the ship.
There's no time. We'll never make it.
Oh, yes, we will.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
Huh?
I.V.A.N.: Self-destruct sequence
complete in ten,
-nine, eight...
-OLD BUZZ: I.V.A.N.? I.V.A.N.!
ROBOT: B-Zurg.
-(WEAPONS WHIRRING)
-Darby, we have to surrender.
No! I am not giving up.
Yep, neither am I. Hold on.
(GASPS)
-(MO AND DARBY SCREAM)
-(ROBOT CHIRPS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
I.V.A.N.: ...five, four...
BUZZ: Let's go.
-I.V.A.N.: ...three, two...
-Everyone, get in.
-...one.
-(YELLS)
(OBJECTS CLANGING)
(ENGINE WHINES)
(BUZZ GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
-(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
We've destroyed the Zurg ship,
and Zurg himself.
Now I just have to catch up
to the Armadillo in order to... (GROANS)
Going somewhere?
I.V.A.N.: Warning,
engine damage is catastrophic.
(ALARM BEEPING)
OLD BUZZ: Buzz Lightyear mission log.
I now have the crystal in my possession
and can finally, at long last,
finish the mission.
I'm gonna go back and matter again, Buzz.
And you?
It will be like you were never here.
-So, prepare to die.
-(WEAPON WHIRS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Not today, Zurg.
-Huh?
-(BUZZ GRUNTS)
(STRAINED GRUNTING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
We've entered the planet's
gravitational pull.
Are we gonna crash?
-I'm afraid so.
-(BOTH WHIMPERING)
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE WHINING)
(GRUNTING)
IZZY: Buzz!
(STRAINING)
I... I can't do it.
Buzz, it's okay. We can.
Can you keep the ship steady?
Yeah. I think so.
(GRUNTS)
Okay. Sox, use the emergency battery
to power up flight controls.
Got it.
I'll need a copilot.
Okay. But I've only done this
in the simulator.
Well, it's about to get real.
Remember, pull back
on the yoke nice and...
-easy.
-Yep, sorry.
Nice and easy from now on.
(ENGINE WHINING)
It's not working.
We're coming in too fast.
-I.V.A.N.
-I.V.A.N.: Yes, Captain?
BUZZ: We're going too fast.
I.V.A.N.: Congratulations!
-(FANFARE PLAYS)
-(COUGHING)
We don't need confetti. We need brakes!
-Oh! I know! The airbrake!
-The airbrake!
-BUZZ: On the floor.
-Darby!
-(GRUNTS) It's stuck.
-What?
The cover, it's stuck.
I need a screwdriver. Or a hairclip.
Or some sort of a small wedge.
(GASPS) I've got the pen!
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
(DARBY GRUNTS)
(BUZZ YELLING)
(PANTING)
-IZZY: Buzz!
-Is everyone okay?
DARBY: Yeah.
MO: Yeah.
-I think so.
-(ALL PANTING)
-(SIRENS WAIL IN DISTANCE)
-The cops! Everybody run!
Wait. It's just the rescue team.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF) Right. Okay.
(CHUCKLES) You seem like a decent citizen.
What led to your incarceration?
I stole a ship.
Oh!
Well, who among us hasn't stolen a ship
in a moment of...
(CLEARS THROAT) relative desperation?
I'm a man of resources.
My weapon is ingenuity.
I can do anything!
Can you not shout in my ear?
Oh, yep, sorry.
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
You okay?
IZZY: (CHUCKLES) I was in space.
Your grandma would be proud.
She'd be proud of you, too.
She always was.
Wait. Where's your crystal?
It's gone.
But your mission...
You wanted to go home.
You know,
for the first time in a long time,
I feel like I am home.
-(LOUD THUMP)
-(ALL GASP)
ROBOT: (CHIRPING) B-Zurg.
Look out!
(WEAPON WHIRS)
-(WEAPON FIRES)
-What?
(POWERING DOWN)
ZAP PATROL: Zap, zap, zap,
zap, zap, zap, zap, zap!
SOLDIER: Stop right now.
(GRUNTS ANGRILY) Lightyear.
You absconded with Star Command property,
stole an experimental spacecraft,
and defied a direct order
from your commander.
I ought to throw you in the stockade.
But I have other plans for you.
We want you to start a new version
of the Space Ranger Corps.
Universe Protection Division.
You're gonna be
a space ranger again, Buzz.
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You can hand-select your team
from the very best
of the Zap Patrol
and train them to your liking.
ZAP PATROL: Zap, zap!
Well, that's very kind of you, sir,
but I'm afraid
I'm going to have to decline.
(ZAP PATROL MURMURING IN CONFUSION)
I already have my team.
(HEROIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CHUCKLES) These new suits are amazing.
Arm blaster, rocket wings.
Could use a pen, though.
Can't believe I'm allowed to carry this.
I wish I had two of 'em.
You got a clean record,
and you're free and armed.
How are you still complaining?
I got off for good behavior,
not good attitude.
You know, I never wear pants,
but suddenly it feels weird
to not be wearing pants.
Does it look weird without pants?
MO: No, you look good.
Wish I could pull that off.
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Look, Grandma, I'm a space ranger.
Just like you.
All right, team. We've picked up a signal
in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector Four.
We don't know what it is,
but we're not gonna wait for it
to invade our home.
Copy, Commander. You can count on us.
Buzz Lightyear mission log, stardate 4071.
As members of the elite
Universe Protection Unit
of the Space Ranger Corps,
we've been charged to protect the galaxy
from the threat of invasion
from any sworn enemies
of the Galactic Alliance.
(BUTTONS BEEP)
Okay, everyone. Make sure
you're securely fastened.
Do we have everything?
-Munitions?
-Check.
-Sustenance?
-I brought sandwiches.
And your tummy will be okay?
-All set.
-All right.
Am I forgetting anything?
I think we're ready.
(BUZZER BLARING)
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
I.V.A.N.: Hello.
I am your Internal
Voice-Activated Navigator.
Good to have you back, I.V.A.N.
CONTROL: Captain Lightyear,
ready for launch.
-Sox?
-SOX: Meow?
Beep, beep, beep, beep.
-Ch-chk!
-I.V.A.N.,
-initiate hyper launch.
-MO: Hmm. Ha-ha!
I.V.A.N.: Certainly.
(ENGINE RUMBLES)
All right, space rangers. Here we go.
To infinity...
BUZZ: And beyond. (MIMICS EXPLOSION)
(MUSIC BUILDING UP TO CLIMAX)
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BUG BUZZING)
(LAUGHS) Laser-shield.
(SLURPS)
DERIC: Now, should you prefer
a more scenic route,
you'll want to head south
past the Bromide Swamps,
a breathtaking sight, or so I am told.
But, if you're in a hurry,
this would be your most direct route.
Any questions?
Hello?
(SIGHS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)